[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
oh welcome my friends you found the
junkyard love podcast
i'm super glad you're here first things
first i always like to start out
something with a good
positive make you think make you think
differently make you go and do something
that switches your mind changes your
perspective
today i'm going to suggest articles of
unity.org articles
of unity 2020. check that out just
search it just figure out what it is
there's gonna be a short video watch it
check that out uh see how it makes you
feel for me
it's like man it makes me feel like
somebody's out there actually taking
care of us somebody's out there actually
trying to brainstorm somebody's out
there being smart
somebody's out there trying to fix this
crazy conundrum
our entire culture and society and place
of home
is facing so check that out articles of
unity and then also
a few other quick things sober october
october is coming up we've got uh the
elections coming up right at the end of
october
beginning of november there i think it's
going to be the most maddening
ridiculous
awful terrible time for people to
communicate with each other
and in light of that i would like to
launch and try to just have everybody
that
wants to be involved do your form of
sober october what i'm going to do and i
have some friends who are doing their
own versions and
we'll get together and hopefully explain
that more um in in the coming weeks
but uh i'm gonna give up caffeine for 31
days in october
i'm gonna do no drinking i'm gonna do no
marijuana i'm gonna do no social media
um and a couple other things i'm gonna
basically have a list of lent
that i am giving up for october and this
is for mental health this is to take
care of myself this is to grab
my own life by the horns um i've done
these these 30 day
you know lengths before and they're just
great because they just really remind
you
that we're just a sack of habits and we
get sucked into our routines and we get
sucked into
um sometimes doing the things that we
don't want to do in light of instant
gratification so
whatever you want to do just get
thinking if you're the one in your
friend group if you're the the homie the
friend group that's the alpha the
the group leader the person who kind of
gets everybody on board
send that text message say yo you guys
want to do our own version of sober
october together
we could we could we could create
ripples joe rogan does this with his
friends and they
they do their own versions if you eat
five candy bars a day
well the month of october try eating
four a day just do your thing man just
find your edge and push against it
whatever you can give up just a little
bit find your edge and push against it
it'll make you a better person
so sober october there'll be more info
on that pretty soon um
something you could do as a listener as
a fan as a friend
as a person who gets benefits from any
of the conversations that i hold i
of course offer these podcasts freely
and i'm so happy to do that but if you
could just share
and just tell people about it and just
you know maybe take some screen
recordings of a
certain section that you liked um just
tell people how to talk about it
show it on your social media whatever
you got to do and the same for these
other guys for these other creators you
know we
we do a lot of this because it's our
passion it's uh what we what we feel is
right
you know so if you could share it i'd
really appreciate that do your thing
one last thing the beginning of the
episode the first like 55 seconds
uh i haven't fully mastered the art of
three person podcasts my interface isn't
exactly up to par for three people so
i've got to do it a little bit
differently
um and no headphones so these take me a
little longer to edit when they're three
person
and uh i also just didn't hit record at
the very beginning
when matt was talking so the first 55
seconds of this episode are gonna sound
bad but i assure you it'll sound
decently after that so just hang in for
the first 55-60
seconds and then it'll sound totally
fine
also take care of yourself my bro if
you're listening to this and you're not
drinking water you're not stretching
you're not smiling
what's your deal what's up with that
take care
of yourself enjoy this episode it's
crazy fire it's
it's oh my god it is it's
hot hot fire the whole way through like
i was editing this back and i'm just
kept getting like jesus
i need to i need to type that out that's
a quote that's a quote that's a quote
these guys
are phenomenal phenomenal motivators
and i'm just super blessed and grateful
to uh
to have such minds open up and and speak
on this platform so
enjoy the episode love yourself
all right hey guys welcome to the
junkyard love podcast we hope you're
having a wonderful day we've got nate
tansman and matt young with us
uh matt i want to start out with you um
listeners if you haven't heard of nate
chancellor we've got a couple episodes
already together you gotta go check
those out
um i'll make him do a little bit of a
bio aftermath here
but uh matt i wanna just go right into
it and hear about this non-profit
organization my guy
um you work with at-risk youth vancouver
elite outreach tell me about this
oh man so uh before i even talk about
the
the mission and what we do uh i i guess
i gotta give a drop back
in the drawback before anything is uh
being gifted but fatherless
okay and so i was a kid that was born in
the inner city lifestyle
and with that i think a lot of people
may um it's like a person looking
outside in but they may not understand
exactly what goes down
in that i guess that development with
the mindset
and so there's a lot of gifted people in
there
but they cannot dream outside their
block and i think
[Music]
if you don't have exposure then you
can't change your experience
and as much as uh it's easier said than
done
get out you have a gift and make better
i don't think it's that easy because
you're dealing with a poverty mindset
and so when you go into these
opportunities where your gift makes room
for you
eventually you might self-sabotage that
opportunity
and so uh i was an example of that
you know i guess the the the
organization started through my own
story
and you know a lot of times people say
have a purpose
but what if you don't ever have a
purpose but there's a bunch of problems
so i allowed the problem to be a purpose
and so
with that opportunity man um
you know went through like suicide just
it's like you're being like this crazy
self-sacrificial person bro and so
it's like so relationships dad issues
trying to make it in basketball loved by
people not being approved all this crazy
crap that we go through in life right
and um the last time i tried to commit
suicide
uh for me it was like it was like this
awakening and i believe that that was
god um
i guess uh showing his love to me but
didn't really understand that
and it wasn't in a way where it was like
you got to go to a church to fill this
presence
i was in a room with my daughter at the
time and
you know when you go through life you
develop traits so the habits for me it
was like
you know at the time when my dad popped
in i knew he was abusive and i think
that stuff jumps
you know and what you're exposed to and
so that's kind of like how it was for me
and so this presence
when i was in the room you know uh
my daughter at the time just uh you know
um was tripping and i feel like when
you're on edge with your
emotions man anything can set you off so
instead of me um
tripping about that it was like i had
this cry
and this cry was like this freedom cry
and all i can remember is me laughing
like it sounds crazy like you know i'm
supposed to be throwing stuff who
probably spanked it but no i laughed and
uh
the next day it was like this feeling i
had like just everything's gonna be okay
and then the next day um i got kicked
out of this place
that i was going house to house in and
my buddy at the time
you know i always say he's my angel he
brought he like came out of nowhere no
phone calls no nothing
and he was like bro uh you're good and i
was like yeah let's just go take my
daughters around he took me to a church
and was bold but the same feeling that i
felt in that room was the same feeling
that i felt
when i was in that church and it was
like this sense of peace and
all the stuff that we try to carry that
is like unseen
was just gone like it's like what's
depression
you know like you can't feel it or
whatever but then you act it
you're acting in a way or what's love
you can't see it but
you manifest this thing it's like a
spirit but it's like oxygen to me
you know you can't see it but i
guarantee you if you go to the moon it's
like if you can't go to the moon without
oxygen you know
you need this thing to live type thing
and so that was like my interpretation
of god you know okay like
man did you have a relationship to god
before this no no
i was like well i was like atheist bro
didn't even know what atheist is because
when you're in these property areas
your vocabulary game ain't really that
fire you know
yeah and so you just like right you just
it just it is what it is
and so and i think that um that that's
where the the communication gap with
everything is off because
when you go on different areas the
vocabulary is amazing and
you use words and different things that
just kind of articulate
a story right yeah yeah yeah and so if
you don't got a vocabulary game
you just kind of use certain things that
you're trying to express or
or tell somebody in your own yeah
because those words like with the
vocabulary
if it doesn't make any sense to you it's
not going to be as profound as it is no
right
right this whole like like language is
such a
hidden tool the more you learn about it
the more you can now understand things
right real quick though i want you to
touch on the environment that you grew
up in
because you're talking about you're
talking about you know you can't grow
outside the block right and you can't
you have this poverty mindset and
you know you grow up in a certain area
so where does that flip and where does
that change like where
where's that awakening come from you
know i'm saying because a lot of people
think that we we put we put caps on
ourselves
you know what i'm saying like this is
this is what this is what i can amount
to and not even
necessarily consciously either so you
you might be putting caps on yourself
that that don't that don't really exist
right
because they don't at all and i firmly
i'm a firm believer in that i think that
there is no cap
but i think that what we do is is what i
was talking about earlier we kind of
attach ourselves to something
so if you attach yourself to the block
and you attach yourself to
the life that you're previously living
where's how how do you grow past that
you know what i mean because then
there's
the pressure of well i got all my
brothers and sisters and i got all my
aunts and uncles and i do i don't want
to make them look bad and then
and then and they're talking to me like
oh you're too good because you know you
you dress different now or you talk
different now are you better than us
because you go
you know so where does that shift you
know what i mean
i mean and that's a good question i felt
like word really shifts for me
is really understanding how to love
yourself
and i think what we do is um everything
we do is
for love to love and to me god is love
right
so so you i can see it because you're
talking about how
family you're wanting to love them so
much that you don't want to
outshine them right or you don't want to
you don't want to make anybody look bad
because you're loving somebody else
right more than yourself right or even
vice versa it could be like
i'm not receiving this love so i'm going
to do these certain things to get love
and and and so for me it was like yo
if i could make it in basketball or any
type of sport because it was like
you know football track baseball
basketball
so out of all these different sports i
tapped in
uh basketball was like the one where it
was like you're not gonna quit
every other sport was more like oh it's
not
fulfilling me quit and then you get this
attention but you create these bad
habits
so you think that do you think that the
sports gave you
a sense of trying to like
getting that like you know so where does
sports tie into
outgrowing the mindset you know what i'm
saying where do sports tie in with um
with kind of just finding your true
potential you know what i mean because i
feel like we're all
man so and so with me and i'ma just be
honest with you everybody don't believe
but i think when you tap into your full
potential it's when you tap into your
spiritual
like there's something about because
it's that it's it and not necessarily
even people that you know aren't
religious right and it's not even about
yeah exactly it's it's the higher self
right
like because spirit is something like i
like i talk about on here man like
spirituality and like
i thought it was all like you see the
word god you see the word religion issue
the word spirituality i thought it was
all [__] that just didn't have anything
to do with me like it's just over there
like i'm like i don't believe in that
it's not me
and like i remember like when i was
younger man i feel like it was just
popular in my family to like make fun of
that sort of [__] and so i never even
thought about it never even looked into
it never even like i just i would crack
a joke if i saw a low hanging fruit
but like not like i had i had similar
like you know spiritual awakening where
i just kind of understood
like what it means to me in that like my
being is love
and like spirit you know i think that we
throw out the baby with the bathwater a
lot when it comes to like
god and spirit and those words just
because the annotation that a lot of us
have on them are like
there's something powerful about being
able to you know spread and like dive
into your own
spirit and figure out what that really
means to you
not not yeah not this big definition
what it means everybody like you can
read
read that and learn that because it'll
spark something to you but every single
time you hear something like this it's
like oh here's what it means to me
no right and so but see and that's that
personal part that i think a lot of
people run from
and it's just like you know when you do
sports or anything
you do it to be approved notice me but
when when does that like break off where
you just are like
forget what being noticed i'm just doing
this because this is what's best for me
and it really took a lot of uh
destruction
bad relationships um not feeling worthy
enough and i remember just when it was
like
all right this was the last relationship
two baby moms in like i'm done
you know i'm done but then it was like
okay i'm gonna self-medicate myself in
this spirituality if jesus does this
thing for me
i'm gonna just go ahead and just
medicate myself and through that
medication it wasn't easy because now
you're dealing with temptation
you're dealing with your ugly self
basically yeah you're bad wolf
right and so it was like okay well
what's my ugly self
females uh pornography um what else
um of anger you know and now it's like
i'm fighting everybody else it's like
remembering
um what's his name uh cassidy the
hustler when he had
the hustler versus uh the problem but it
was like a
like a battle it's the same person but
it's two
identities yeah i feel like there's this
constant
tug of war between
your whatever is going on with you and
then your higher self and
and i i truly believe like what what
isn't in your best interest is somehow
in somebody else's best interest
like if you are not on your [__] if
you're
falling to your vices or your um
or your uh you know uh your temptations
right
that benefits somebody else right that
benefits somebody
that might be a a woman or a man for
instance that might be going after you
because you're in a relationship because
people do do that
that benefits them if you have a problem
that you need to be affirmed guess who
benefits off that
louis vuitton does come on you know what
i'm saying so that's what i feel like if
it's
something something that you do or
something that you place
not in your best interest is upon
somebody else's like even if it's the
littlest things like even if you
miss workouts you know and or i mean
that
i think that everybody is their own
process but to me it's like i'm not
missing workouts because
i don't want anybody to ever say that i
was off my game because that's in
somebody else's best interest to say oh
look at nate's not on a [__]
he's not doing what he said he was going
to do he's just a talker like
i don't care what people think but it's
important to me
that i am in myself that i can say that
i'm always doing for what's in my best
interest nobody can say
to me even if it doesn't affect me i
don't even want it to be a conversation
and
again i don't want it to fall to if i'm
not doing what's best for me then i'm
out
spending vicariously if i'm not doing
what's best for my interest in my family
with my girl
i'm sliding dms like because that's in
somebody else's best interest that's not
in mine so i feel like when you fall
temptation or you fall weakness or you
have vices like
that's good for somebody else you know i
mean what's not in your best interest
is in somebody else's best interest no
matter what decision you make
and i feel like the problem is in these
days is that
psychological marketing is a very real
thing
like it's our whole society we're
talking the very most important thing in
a business is psychological marketing
i don't i hate to to to be like that
people and businesses and all these
things are evil but
they have to sell their products and how
do you sell a product
yeah of course a product has to be good
but also that
i know you listen a lot to tony robbins
tony robbins says that people buy
feelings i'm buying a feeling
louie gucci i'm buying a status i'm
buying i'm buying something that makes
me feel a certain way
whether i can afford it or not this
makes me feel some type of way
when i indulge myself in this when i
drink when i buy something
when i when i eat bad food like all
these people are profiting off of that
people are lazy right so that's why we
have fast food well fast food's bad for
you well guess what
nobody wants to cook nobody wants to
prep their meals nobody wants to go to
the grocery store because there's 10
things you have to do in order to eat
healthy
you know what i mean but guess what we
have it taken care of for you
drive to the drive-thru we're gonna have
it done in less than in less than a
minute
see how that goes they're fulfilling a
need but
that need in their best interest is not
in your best interest at all
and so that's why i feel like again i
feel like psychological marketing is a
real thing and i feel like it's
going on right now with with with all
the problems that are in the world right
now too
the pandemic and all i've seen so many
new
products that are keeping people safe
that people are just buying up because
people are creating fear in them
so people are creating fear in you and
now you know i can't wear one of those
masks the blue ones that are 99 cents i
got to get one with the logo on it so
now you got me for 25 bucks
you know what i'm saying because i i
can't wear that i can't wear that
because people are going to judge me
people are going to judge me i can't
wear that
right it's just crazy so false yeah
they're telling us like things that we
should be fearful of so we're trying to
fight those fears it sucks
dude i think so like look at this
conversation right now like our age
dudes
like like for younger kids growing up
dude for young kids growing up i just
feel scared for them like to like
they're not in control of their own
minds they're like
people who some 23 year old like
like uh computer programmer who lives in
silicon valley
is controlling like what the young kids
are thinking about like because he's
like i i have the marketing skills i
have the degree and
and he puts the data out there because
it makes the money you know
like having these conversations like so
it seems like we've all had some form of
like spiritual awakening
of of of some form you know and
we all have that means something to each
of us as individuals of course
but i think there's a lot of people our
age like uh millennials or whatever you
want to call it who are like
experiencing this and we're like wait
hold up like we don't want to just
do the same habits that our parents did
we don't want to just do this [__]
and so like like but being able to talk
to it talk about it now
is is so great um i think that
when it comes to like this awakening
it's kind of like it's hard to not see
it as like this like global like there's
a lot of people are going through this
sort of thing
and i'm just kind of curious like what
do you guys think the future for young
people
is going to be now so like all the [__]
that we went through like we had to
learn the hard way
like now these kids are like you know a
lot of them are listening to people like
us who are like don't
don't do it the way we did it we learned
so you don't have to you know it's it's
almost kind of like
there's more like you know father big
brother figures popping up
but it's also we're teaching like it's
not about us it's not about idolizing us
at all it's about
in inside you all the answers are within
you yeah
yeah yeah i i man i i have
the problem is is that dudes like us
don't sell
and that's an issue so i think that
as much as there is i feel like there's
more stuff happening like
like what's going on right now these
conversations right now but i also think
that
mainstream media and hip hop
has way more play and way more money i
mean that's just what it is there's no
there's no competition between a
conversation like this and a drake song
there's no competition and bro drake's
my favorite
catchy drake's my favorite rapper but
but listen to what he's saying right so
you have a 12 year old listening to that
talking about sex and talking about this
and talking about that
i'm not i'm not any kind of saint but
i know what's not healthy and it's
everything that's in those damn songs
but you know what so that's funny that
you say that because so you know how
tuesday right we did that event
and what i realized with that event it
was like
okay we got to give these kids more than
that uh
we got to give them more than just a
word
and then a basketball game what do they
want what's the need
kids want clothes kids want shoes what's
deeper than a need
hey let's find a kid right that parents
may be struggling with a bill
as us being this business or whatever we
want to label ourselves
as how do we fulfill that but then say
right here
we all have 25 to give right how do we
put that in the pot just to bless
not touch but the thing is
it's like when you have a poverty mind
you have hoarder mentality the hoarder
mentality for me that i feel like i'm
growing out of
is she's asking for five dollars
and then instead of me giving that five
dollars because i have the five dollars
to give i'm thinking about
but what if i need the five dollars so
then i don't
or instead of you know being that
blessing i'm judging
and then the judging talks me out of
blessing and so
with this opportunity that we have yeah
drinking them is hot and they're doing
their things but they're not being
tangible
you have to give to get we're just
giving to give
you know yeah as i watched um
an eric thomas speech one time and he
said he said he was talking about that
he said that there was a rapper in town
and he he didn't go to school but e.t
was there you know i'm saying he gets
paid 50 g's to speak
right but he's at the school for free
right the rapper's not there
right he came and took something from
you he took your money but he didn't
invest nothing back into you
and i feel like obviously these people
are busy we get it you know i mean
and and they have what but hey hang on
hang on
but no but hang on but think about but
yo think about how many
that is that that is there that you're
at the point where you
at that level you're in a selfish
mentality how many things you have to
book how many things you have to do
bro if you're going to be if you're
going to spend 2 mil on a boat you ain't
going to want to go on it like you know
what i'm saying like
i'm not saying that's i don't like that
that's not how i get down
but think think about all that right but
that i feel like all we can do is chip
away
but at this point there's this
conversation in this
table is never we're literally so far
underground compared to mainstream music
and mainstream
marketing we don't have the money nor
the
computer power nor the knowledge that
these people have because
of the disgusting amounts of money that
they do have that we don't even know
about
we can't get there like well why not why
can't we get there
bro you're talking about i mean it's a
possibility
but at this point you're talking about
you're talking bro
everything is controlled by
i'm a conspiracy i really i think that i
don't think the government controls the
government i think the people with money
control the government
oh no doubt i mean that's not even
conspiracy
honestly i just i just feel like that's
what it is i mean you see these people
that are certain types of
beliefs right and then you have people
that run companies that they
put their content out on and then they
get taken down
you know what i'm saying because they
have a different it's not weird it's
it people are like oh that just somehow
got deleted it's like no go on google
you see this person's a republican i do
it all the time and when people say oh
this video got deleted i go watch the
video i find it somewhere else
i look up their political views i look
up the person that owns that company's
political views and it's always
different
see ya cancel bye so that's the problem
is that when these people have so much
power
and so much money if you say something
that they don't
like or you're spitting facts or you're
talking about stuff that might wake
people
up that might stop them from spending
their money there
see ya goodbye that's what we can't
compete with right now
you know what i mean so we're out here
talking about
things that people are gonna profit off
of self-development right
um you know invest in yourself don't
invest in this uh
vaccine what right whatever this
whatever we're talking about that people
are gonna make money off of if we're
trying to take it away
you've seen it happen you see all those
things on instagram where people talk
about
how bad that this is and how bad that is
and they don't know what they're doing
with the vaccine and then it's
it's not tested on anybody it's not boom
gone it's gone
it disappears yeah dude it's the
controlled narrative it's the controlled
narrative well so okay there's something
though
like if if you really 100
thought that that was the only thing
like this is practically i'm not that's
not what you're saying i know but this
is
close to pointless because we're
fighting like machines basically with
data and algorithms and stuff
there's clearly something within all
three of us
right oh that's funny but we're
we are fighting though we aren't i mean
yeah no i mean it's it's true
there's no doubt about it but there's
still something within all three of us
at this table that fights the nihilism
right because like here we are still
like
i've got less than 100 followers on my
youtube bro and i'm still doing this
every day like my
the podcast doing good but like i'm
still just like
i have this thing within me now that's
just like this service where i'm like
i don't know i i can't waste my whole
time trying to figure out these
algorithms i can't waste my whole time
trying to get the right video in front
of the right people but i know what i
could do today is just do the work and
record the video
and put it out there see now see so yeah
so and that's what it is because i think
when we focus so much on i guess making
it so pretty
how much time was that so if i could
just pump out
and be consistent just with what i'm
doing man i might spark up somebody that
actually knows how to do it in 10
seconds
to you know but your gift will make room
for you
and so instead of us just worrying about
ah this sounds
no i'm just to produce and keep going
and keep going because it's just like
when we watch film the movies
um different artists they're consistent
they don't even have to be good nowadays
but if you're just consistent and you
can do what people can't do
they're going to gravitate so in this
thing that we're doing you know
especially just
with our youtube channel speaking from
the heart it's an opportunity for
us to just speak that real and be true
but then how do you like you're saying
well how do we make more
well look they must shut down i heard on
monday that doesn't mean that we stopped
tuesday
you know we just got to continue to go
and make
like you said servitude that just
reminds me of this verse but he said
jesus didn't come to
be served but to serve and give his life
away for as a ransom for many
i'm willing if this is the end of the
world i'm willing to give my life
away as a ransom now be in the house
cooped up in fear and then die
i'm gonna be out there on the forefront
and then die in faith yeah really so
the the titanic when it went down man
the the people the musicians at the end
like that was a real thing i guess they
literally just said all right [__] it
like we're going down this ship is
sinking right now
grab your bow let's sit down we're
playing they played music while the
titanic sank bro
like you got like that's what it is and
i i think that that
that within humans is like really worth
shining a light on because i think that
that's
like there's many of people right now
who are trying to find that spark in
them or that the spark is coming out in
them and they didn't even know they
don't know nothing about it like a lot
of i just post some on instagram
uh today is like i think because of the
pandemic and all just this craziness
right now like tons of people are going
through similar awakenings that we went
through like
they're they're a little bit after us
but like
is there ways that we can guide them you
know like there's a lot of
doing them they don't want to listen you
know like because it hurts it triggers
them but like in a couple of months you
know
we've been there like you gotta slowly
sneak into what's like ooh like that's
too painful to deal with right now yeah
you gotta slowly sneak into your [__]
you know i feel like
the pandemic is it was either i feel
like there was no in between like i feel
like nobody
coasted people either got miles better
they got miles worse i mean think about
it you have
all the time in the world to sit
with yourself like do you know how hard
that can be for some people bro that's
scary though
because because that's what i'm saying
with yourself isn't that crazy
yeah so because everything like all
these
all these these these vices and all
these things that we're talking about
there are no more like the things that
you
do or the things that you that are
driven by by
affirmation instead of instead of
self-fulfillment
those things were cancelled you can't
drive anywhere in your car because
you're not supposed to leave your house
all those clothes
and all those shoes and all the watches
that you the bars are closed
like do you know how hard that is for
some people to to have
and that's why i personally what
happened to me is that when i had got my
accident everything that i valued was
taken from me
so this is how i identify right i didn't
i wasn't like oh i'm a good person you
know i know that when things go wrong
you know i'll still be here i'm loyal
but no i was like i'm
i have i look good and i have a bike
gone [__] gone your identity is like
stripped away so that's why i tell
people like when when i did that
i felt like one of my better speeches
was that character speech right
it was a man is judged by times when no
one is around
when he gets nothing in return right who
are you when you don't have
anything no right like that's what i
want to know like and that's why i think
people need to understand
and this is
the youth and where we need to awaken
the youth is we need to ask those
questions
take certain people that you look up to
take their money who are they
right who are they right like bro what
do these people do
they're not doing nothing for you right
they're not they're not they're not
borrowing out with you
they're not sitting down with you and
talking to you hey you know how's things
going at home
right they don't care but let me say
this though so to me
you know how like when we had all this
stuff going on you got the pandemic you
got race wars right
a lot of people are talking about um
systematic racism
i was talking to the buddy and i said
people got to understand that systematic
slavery is alive and a lot of us don't
understand that we're free slaves
come on we're free it's kind of like
i'll let you go so far but once you go
in this
invisible fence and you go past
i got to go back but what is that it
could be shoes
it could be it's yours your vices right
your vices and your insecurities
are what makes us free slaves people
wake up every day
not because they want to or not because
they want to do something because they
have to because they're in a hole
right i have this car i have this i have
that i have to make a certain amount of
money
to maintain my lifestyle that is all
based upon
impressing people that you don't [__]
know or like
you were you were slave we're trapped in
a life they sold to us
exactly that's what i'm saying that's
that's psychological marketing
all right all right so let's switch but
let's switch so like like right now so
so this is [__] that everybody knows
right like everybody's like
well maybe not everybody maybe they
don't want to admit where where we're at
as individuals
but everybody kind of knows like yeah i
know we're kind of like suckers to the
system like
we're in it like what can we do so what
can we do like what what do young kids
right now who just graduated and they
didn't get to go to graduation 2020 like
like what what can we tell them like
what's what are the things
because like we're not going to have
magical answers to three of us that's
for sure but we can
focus on the things that we have focused
on so like what's your story how do you
change your story
matt i feel like i feel like you've got
good perspective on this you want to
talk about change in your story i mean
so like
tony robbins is a good one that i think
of he he has this story where
he was younger and essentially like
someone knocked on the door they were
low income they didn't have much money
they didn't have a
thanksgiving dinner and someone knocked
on their door
through you know people through people
someone had heard they didn't have
enough money for a thanksgiving dinner
and someone came and said
someone cares about you we want we know
that you guys are struggling or whatever
it was we want to give you this dinner
and tony robbins dad said we don't take
charity get out of here slam the door in
his face those sort of things
and so he he takes that instead of like
keeping that history for the rest of his
life it's like
we're just poor people we don't take
charity he says he saw it
you know as a different way of like he
wants to make sure nobody else feels
that way he wants to he wants to serve
he wants to be the person on the outside
of that door you know he so he shifted
his story
um yeah have you heard that no i haven't
heard that story because i
like so so with me when i first got into
like stuff
i guess i was like oblivious to who are
who was already doing things
and so all these big namers like you
know inky johnson
tony robbins you know uh eric thomas uh
les brown all these things so i wasn't
really into
that but it was kind of like i was on my
own journey
and i guess just like when i did ball
i didn't like idolize these people
because
all that time that i could be watching
them what am i doing with me
and so i guess where i'm at where we
talk about making that difference and
making that change is kind of like once
you
know who you are and you love who you
are now
and you know how i said um you know your
problem becomes your purpose
now you start looking at what is the
need and through that need for instance
we were saying like i wanted to be what
i needed when i was younger
so i needed mentorship i needed
resources
you know um i needed uh you know
opportunity right
exposure so now through this
organization vancouver lee outreach
before we even get into the service that
we do
you obviously our our stuff is different
from everybody else but what makes us
different is all about what we believe
so we believe in enhancing the
individual to be the best version of
themselves
and then we believe in thinking
differently better mind better lifestyle
and i think when you get to that point
where
you're crafting that and you said you go
well how do you continue to go we do a
piece called open up your blind side
that's our curriculum that we use but
it's an inner work
that you're doing and then through that
inner work that you're doing if it's
testimony if it's agendas or
you hear something just like this this
stuff is going to do
um insight within for us to question or
uh i never thought about that but then
it's what you do with that
like at the end of the day you know uh
this is um
john c maxwell says this thing that i i
went to one of his things he said
a c t apply change teach
that spells act but we have all these
time
all this time to be acting on things but
again if you're not applying you're not
changing and you're not teaching
you're not each one teach one and
nothing it's like free game
like everything that we have is not
created for me it's free
and that's what i think that there's
like this selfishness of
big time that's the place yeah yeah
because because
people people don't want to give the
game away right but the
the problem is is that you got the game
from somebody
most likely for free come on like but
but when you have this breakthrough or
you have an idea or you
p and that's that poverty mindset so the
point is
is that when people figure out something
that's how they generally make money
right
think about it like think about et like
what if he woke up and
that's just my guy but what if he woke
up and was like oh i don't want to
i don't want to tell people about how i
broke through
right his breakthrough became
his income right like but nobody does
that so and that's why i like
what i um think is so
different about vancouver really i've
always told you that i always think that
you're different i always think that
your time is coming i always always
but i think that it's your
your mission is not to build the
business is to build the individual
right and then the individuals build the
business no come on and that's what
people don't get
is people have such a large focus on how
how do i
um how do i scale you know how do i get
bigger how do i reach more people
you reach more people by reaching the
people that are right in front of you
right
right because that's what it is because
i there was 40 kids at that thing the
other day
all word of mouth all because somebody
said that
and that's what i and that's what i
think is so powerful about
matt is that you know you have guys like
him
that these kids are going through the
same thing that he went through they
automatically trust him
like they don't and you know he works
with kids with the inner city like
these kids that they don't they don't
want to go to school because they don't
respect their teachers because they
don't know their teachers because their
teachers don't talk like that
when you have a guy that's talking like
yo i've i have that you know
i was this this old with with a child i
was you know
a victim of this victim of that you know
abuse you know all this like
parents like they trust that
vulnerability they trust
you and exactly and they wouldn't come
if they didn't trust you they wouldn't
come right but you know and
and the thing is because some people say
like but what if i don't have that
lifestyle
if i don't have that lifestyle can i not
tap in
and i believe that you don't have to
basically
go through suffering to tap in you just
got to be real
right and being here but everybody has
problems truly yeah
but but so like for instance i work on
the east side right
and i'm working with kids that
financially
are good they're not going to get
evicted you know
uh 40 acres basketball hoop go car you
know golf carts just
the life right and
when i'm out there i don't have to say
hey you need to make more that is
why don't you tell them about making
money i need to get like under him and
how do i
what what's the secret what because
those kids have their own problems
right so those kids have their those
problems is
i feel like i grew up that in a similar
way my parents didn't have money
but i never earned anything and and that
created a false sense
of reality for me because
nothing is [__] given to you not
nothing you earn
[__] everything your self-development
your confidence everything even
not even in the external but the
internal this self
all this self development [__] is
[__] earned every day your positive
attitude is earned every day when you
battle your
your negativity your exactly your mental
health your physical health
everything is [__] earned but when
you grow up and you have everything
handed to you i feel like you're at a
disadvantage
you really are and so you know everybody
wants to talk about people you know that
grew up and they were privileged and
blah blah blah
like we were talking about earlier every
i personally think that everything has
as much positive as it does negative
so you got a kid yeah he didn't struggle
when he was younger he didn't have to
eat he didn't have to but he had
everything he [__] wanted so then
when he gets kicked out in the world
he's confused why it's not coming to him
so you have kids like that
you can like you instead of you talk
them
into their positivity like hey bro like
you got it real good
you know like you don't have to work
maybe during high school like some of
these other kids do you can be in the
gym that much longer right
you know what i'm saying right you use
that to your advantage yeah i mean so
you can still coach those kids
and still mentor those kids in a mental
state because it's
bro life is to me is is 99 mental and
one percent physical
literally and that goes along with
everything and my and my thing is
because you know like
you know that event was so amazing but i
don't just credit me
like the opportunity was for everybody
and then whoever came got empowered that
wanted to be
and i think the thing that keeps me
grounded a lot is
i'm just a baker that found bread
and that keeps me where it's like i'm
chilling bro like
and that mentality people like but
you're putting yourself down no i'm not
because i'm still
seeing what's going on in my life that
is changing
but who am i to be like
you know because i feel like once you
feed the ego then that's when i feel
like you're just gonna crash and burn
your own
stuff and and i think uh
a lot of times it's kind of like we look
for that and then what happens if we
don't get that affirmation
then the world is over and so it's just
like
bro i'm just like i said i'm a baker bro
like you know what's crazy to me is that
i feel like
a lot of things are driven in this
psychological marketing world about the
ego so
and that's why i posted something on
instagram because it was like a really
interesting thought to me
was everything that you do your whole
entire life the way that
your thoughts your habits everything
right
is that based upon affirmation
or is it based upon fulfillment and the
ego is about
affirmation there is no there's no
affirmation in in i'm sorry there's no
ego and self fulfillment don't they
don't they don't align
like it they're not in the same
conversation you can have one or the
other
like and and that's what i feel like and
and
greatness requires to me
self-fulfillment not affirmation not not
not all this like you know go chasing
something
that never will be and it because i mean
man that's been
it's been hard for me man i've had to
check my ego
and i feel like i'm at the point where
sometimes it i it still gets in the way
because it's a habit
but greatness requires it greatness
requires checking your ego like you know
how many people have had to ask for help
that i want to ask for help from
then i have to look at somebody that
might be younger than me and ask them
how they how they make their money like
how how did you get here how'd you get
there like i asked people about their
journey about their process is like
somebody could look at me and i was like
you don't have it together like
you older than me i'd be like yeah but
i'd be like scratch all that because
this
even just like the other day right
there's this young 18 year old
filmer he was on the news right
and i'll be dumb in a
direction that i'm trying to go but i
have no information so then i'll be
foolish basically not asking for
guidance
but then when we do that it's kind of
like
no i'm not going to ask because i don't
want to seem like because i'm this age
agent got no number bro like so so to
battle those
so that's where i feel like you have to
check the ego you have to deal with
those insecurities you have to deal with
like
how's this going to make me look and
that's what i mean by saying
that's not how how you look to somebody
else is not about self-fulfillment those
are not in the same conversation right
yeah bro all right so so let's see i was
like trying to define ego in the moment
i heard this thing
um that helped start out cause like i
feel like when i was i didn't understand
the word ego i thought i did i thought i
just meant you're cocky as hell that's
what i thought
but like the more you learn about it and
you like learn about like what
like eastern philosophy has to say about
it and like how it's just
changed like essentially i like to think
of it for any listeners who like don't
know what the [__] the ego is it's just
think the beginning
you got just a bunch of like right
before we became humans we were in
evolution we were just monkeys right so
we're just
we're all in a circle and we're talking
and eventually we're like we got to
start naming some [__] right we're going
to be able to have conversation we got
to form a union somehow
so instead of just like pointing out
things like is that good to eat
water bottle or you're like you hold up
a banana and you're like banana and
these are
words this is how we create a language
right of course i wasn't there i don't
[__] know
but like we're we're naming things and
eventually we had to point at each other
and say
nate we had to say matt and that's the
start of like
our societal identification so
if you try to try to remember that when
you're being pointed at like
your ego is kind of your your society
societal identifier in your group so
it's kind of hard because it starts to
go to this like it doesn't really exist
sort of
world but it's essentially like it can
it because i don't think it does well
it's we think that it does we operate as
if it does because that's just how
life has like worked out but when you
could realize when you're doing
something like oh is this just something
that i'm doing
for the namesake wanting to fit in
like my name my ego wanted to fit in
with its environment with its group
um when it comes to ego it all gets
super confusing but i
i will say that anybody who does any
sort of like
googling on on the word ego just look up
youtube video doesn't matter who it is
learn about it man and there will be
things within each of us that'll spark
and we'll be like
oh okay and it's almost kind of like
where can i call myself out at
that's do you feel like the ego is like
the ego is of the present self's battle
with the higher self is that the ego is
that what stands in between
i mean kind of i mean i mean when you
talk like your bad wolf your good wolf
when you talk like spirit consciousness
it kind of seems like your ego is kind
of your lower conscious stuff
and your your higher self is is spirit
right don't you think i mean when
wouldn't you think that the ego would be
right in between right
i mean it's got to exist no it has to
but it's just like saying like flesh and
spirit
you know yeah because i feel like that's
the ego is what causes reaction right
so say you with all the [__] going
on right you have like a chance to
argue with somebody you have a chance to
be physical right
so if someone's talking [__] the ego is
i'm going to make this rational
irrational decision right
right and then the higher self is like
i'm going to walk away that little voice
yeah right i
i think that i've wow i think that's
what stands in between the two
honestly yeah but what's crazy too so i
was at this
um counseling thing with my daughter
right and his child play
during child play everything stems off
of feelings
right and then in feelings
depending on whatever the circumstance
is like maybe you fail
now you have learned that in your mind
when you fall
daddy reacts this way if you fall mommy
reacts this way
so it's kind of like the movie inside
out you got all this
in your head that are you know basically
making moments off your feelings who's
to say if it's right or not
but because it's in our head we
now it's right but then when you get
awoke you're gonna be like whoa
no like it's just like like now that
we're in a society where if you whoop
your kids
you're gonna just they can call the cops
and say you i got abused pick him up
no right no fraud the kids are like hey
i gotta abuse my
mom right but in that old way of
learning that way and it's not
it was just for that time right because
everything evolves
now in this time i feel like we're
coming back where you can express
yourself
everybody but everybody say put yourself
when you do that no
i think expressing your feelings is a
healthy way but then
how do you channel whatever it is that
you're trying to channel hey i made me
feel this way that doesn't mean i'm soft
i don't you're setting boundaries and so
i feel like
how do we just even just like where
we're at with self
how do we be the best of ourselves
because i can't you know at the end of
the day and just like this like if i'm
like nate
you need to get better you need to do
this you might let that slide a couple
of times
but if i go a lifetime and a like a
job-wise and telling you
you need to get better and either then
you hear that all the time
she said through child play your your
first emotion is anger
you're gonna be like mad bro like i
heard you like
i'm something time shut up bro now boom
now boom and they're just building
blocks and i feel like
i don't know i feel like because
everything's so jacked up
it's kind of like all you really can do
is save yourself
but influence everybody else but how do
you influence
not this but with this i think
everything has
i think everything has a line and
everything has a perspective
i personally think that i've taken time
to reflect and and i do think that
certain types of
i think expression is very important but
i think the action behind
expression is equally as important i
personally do think that our society is
soft
i really do why because
you can't say something without
offending somebody
and if you offend somebody somebody can
pull the plug on you somebody can
call the cops on you somebody can um
blast you on facebook somebody like
those i think expression is very
important i do i
express myself a lot that's why we're
all sitting here is because we're
expressing ourselves we're expressing
our feelings we're expressing our
emotions we're talking about all three
of us have
talked about committing suicide that's
expression but
the line to me is where you become a
victim
so i think all three of us
are obviously sitting here and sharing
this in confidence right
but if you are the you know i've thought
about killing myself like you know
i just i have all these disadvantages
because i like people don't know what
i've been through because i thought
about killing myself you're
you're a victim at that point i think
that's
that victim is part is what makes us
soft
like if someone does something to you
that's a reflection of them and that's
what people don't get
like i tell people talk about um
when i was bartending and i'd have you
know people come in and
talk about their relationships right
people always have this like
thing where they have this huge hit to
their ego because they got punked or
they got played
like where where was this ever a thing
that you took it offensively that
someone knew
some very personal information about you
and got you in a vulnerable state and
they did something [__] up and you
took that upon yourself
that's not on you and that's a that's
what's going on is that people are
taking
everybody else's opinion and holding it
so high
that that's what creates that victim
mentality it's like
so-and-so said this someone still said
that they're doing this they're doing
that they're telling me this they're
telling me i can't amount to this
they're telling me i can't amount to
that
taking that opinion personally
and and and letting it affect you that
is
a part of being to me is mentally soft
there's some sort of i feel like last
time we podcasted i had a different
outlook but i feel like now with the
quarantine and stuff i really do
feel like there's some sort of grid that
has to be applied to your mind
like there has to be some sort of guard
that you place up and some sort of like
i don't know what the word i guess the
word would be great but like
yeah because bro i could let that
happen all the time like you can let
that happen all the time you could let
that happen all the time
like do you how do how do you feel about
how do you feel about growing up in the
hood how do you feel about being black
right now
how do you feel about all this how do
you feel but but oh you know man it was
really hard for me
right you know like and i'm not saying
this is a racial thing but i'm saying is
this everybody has
those things that they can cling on to
right you
had your father was a drug addict how do
you feel about that jake are you okay
are you doing all right
like are you gonna make it you know i i
mean they almost make you identify your
i'm really glad that you're sitting here
in such a positive way jake
you know it's it's great it's like no
[__] that like
and i feel like everybody has this
narrative that they can cling on to
that is either positive or negative like
we talked about the good wolf and the
bad wolf the ego and the thing because
this feeds me like
whatever you can get something out of
negativity
right tony robbins talks about that
human needs when i don't work out i
still get one of my needs met
because i'm i'm i'm feeling one of those
needs of
feeding an insecurity or feeding an
addiction to food or
when i used to it's crazy enough is that
i had gone through
i so here's the victim and i'll do it
myself was my stomach issues that we
talked about okay
from 18 and this is just straight up
real and this is like the first time
that i've told this publicly
from 18 to 26 bro i would literally
[__] my pants all the time i would
shower in the [__] bathroom at lcc
i would throw my underwear away i have
to shower in the bathroom at the gym
clean myself up at the gym clean myself
up at [__] nike bro
like people don't know that but i held
on to that
and i didn't realize until my girl
brought it up to me what does that do
for you
do do people feel bad for you do you get
attention from it and i [__] was
i was telling people that oh you know i
got stomach issues like you know
i don't really like and it was a [__]
excuse it was an excuse for me
i held on to it you know i really can't
be as good of the athlete as i want it
to be
because i have stomach issues and i
can't hold food and i can't keep weight
on so
why did you feel the need to keep that
as part of your story it was a
subconscious
it wasn't a conscious thing i really
thought that there was something wrong
with my [__] stomach but there wasn't
like i had all these emotional issues
and i knew about it i was like hey
every time something bad happens to me
whatever's in me is clearing out right
away like bro i'm talking
i've had times within seconds like my
first girlfriend was like hey i don't
love you anymore
within seconds i had to go to the
bathroom so i know
subconsciously that is an emotional
thing because that's not
that's not biological or what's the
what's the word for body biological
right
okay that's not a biological thing you
can't just hear someone say hey i don't
love you anymore and you have to take a
[__]
it doesn't work like that that's
emotional and
and i was like oh okay so i can tell
somebody this
and the reason that i don't want anybody
to think that i'm going after people or
coming at people's throats so that's all
i'll talk about myself
like because everybody has some sort of
way that they've done this right
i was like oh i could tell people that
like well [__] nate you work out every
single day like you're not that big well
i have stomach issues
like i can't keep waiting bro like oh
yeah you've been hitting the gym but
like man it looks like you're
oh yeah well you know i've lost 10
pounds this week because i take a [__]
every five minutes
like i held on to it i use it as a
[__] excuse
and i it wasn't till i got to the point
where i started controlling my stomach
and my mind
and all this other [__] until i was like
[__] that i can do whatever i want i'm
not a [__] victim
this is not gonna control me and i feel
like people let their narrative control
them and that's why i say
that society is soft because you can
attach yourself to something
now and because we live in such a social
media era
i can post something i can contact
somebody that's feeling that same thing
and we can be [__] sorry together you
got a community for it bro i follow a
ton of stuff on reddit about that same
thing like
the depression subreddit the uh anxiety
subreddit like all these different
subreddits i would follow
because there was part of me that like
experienced it as just someone like i
wanted someone to listen to me
well i didn't post but i wanted someone
to relate to rather um so i'd have that
but a lot of times like as i would kind
of like start to look at my own issues
and you know
heal from them and start to understand
them more you know a couple of years i
was like you know i don't really think
this is all your credits anymore exactly
i started looking in like
the amount of people that you know as
humans we need somebody you know
sometimes that's a lot of that first
step i was like let's just get let's
just get us listened to but a lot of
times the
subreddits the communities would just be
like reaffirming
our our stories that are hurting us you
know and there's but there's this
balance though so like
we the way we identify ourselves like i
was watching one of your videos you're
talking about um dyslexia
and like a lot of times it's like we're
waiting for you know
companies or like like oh you got adhd
you got add you got depression you got
anxiety you got all
all these things are like you don't have
to identify with them man like
yeah they're trying to tell you what you
have so they can sell you a drug
and a lot of this stuff is just like you
figure out the way you are accept it and
then
work on it and see but see and i like
that you say that because
i think i think the reason why people
fall into the victim mentality
because nobody's saying that there's a
different way out
so when you see people or maybe you
might be in because it's easy
but well they're unaware of where it's
easy right but so this like with me
when i was dealing with dyslexia i never
heard somebody say
you could be better so in my
my little bubble or whatever it was like
oh your son's mentally [__]
oh this is what up iep so
it wasn't like somebody's saying yeah so
i think that's where the system
starts getting us it's right there right
where you're at
but now they're ready now they're ready
to sell you a drug right right now
they're ready to put you in a different
classroom right now they're ready to
take more money from your parents right
that's where the system gets us right we
we
we're susceptible we're susceptible to
what's wrong with us not what's right
with us because when something is right
with us
they can't [__] sell us anything
right right so i was talking about your
uh your friend um the girl the
the um jordan jordanelle right
she can't be [__] sold anything
because she doesn't need anything
i was te i was listening to a podcast
bro this chick lives in a house with no
running water and no electricity
she's so mentally grounded they can't
[__] sell her [__] right she's not
buying anything
she's not being told where she's wrong
and and what's wrong with her and
obviously everybody there's no there's
no end of the battle obviously
but she's very far ahead like after i
listen that episode i almost questioned
myself i was like bro could you do that
could you give up everything are you
able to get off your [__] phone
let's be honest are you able to get off
your phone are you able to not have
electricity
are you able to go out and pump the
thing so you can drink water and who are
you after all that and who you
are you after that what's funny is so
before i move with rachel
my roommate you know at the time when i
was going through all my craziness
it was like i was getting basically
freed from all this
like slavery so when i moved into his
house
he uh didn't have tvs
and so it made you put it be in a
position where you know normally it's
like you interact this way right
no you got board games you're reading
it's more
intimate and we did that for two years
and it was so amazing because everything
we did was intimate
and a lot of times what you know you're
talking about you know this stuff or
what's going on
is this is feeding us something
that may be killing us you know it is
feeding something that's killing us
because that's where
it bro the only dollar rules you know
but we're but we're in a way where it's
like it's entertaining we
like we justify it oh this is it's just
a show
yeah i just need a couple of laughs man
i worked all day i need to right right
so the justification comes from the
identity what you were talking about
earlier so you're talking about
identifying something
that's where the justification comes
from and that's why people you have to
be careful what you identify with and
the only reason that i
started to get healthy was because my
girl was telling me all that so when you
identify with something
everything that belongs in that
lifestyle goes along with it right
depression all this other stuff like all
those lifestyle things
go along with that and then your whole
life changes in a different direction
that whole it's all perspective
i'm feeling sad today is not i'm i i'm
suffer from depression you know what i
mean
right right right um my heart's beating
fast i i feel like
um i feel like i'm short short of breath
right now is not
i have massive major anxiety attacks
like it's like you know
i'm always trying to like stop time
right now and score ourselves and define
ourselves for that we're always trying
to define ourselves right [__] now
but life
this whole thing is just constantly
moving like that's not it's not really
how it works like
who you say you are today like what does
that have to do with who you're gonna
say you are when you're 60 years old
like it's always moving yeah and that's
why i feel like
um i want to i think one of the
one of tony robbins human needs is
something along those lines of
identifying with something or being a
part of something a contribution or
how it is that um it's something that
that attaches you to something
that's uh it's something that's
programmed in you that's never gonna
stop happening
so fi you better [__] figure out
something that makes it so you're
positive or it makes it so
you can do what you want to do and you
can be happy and you can be fulfilled
because
if you're not attaching yourself to that
you're going to attach yourself to
something else i don't think that
there's
any gray area like i think that if
you're not growing then
you're you're dying i mean there's
figuring it out is in a positive
direction
and that's what people don't understand
when people i feel like people
do this negative self-talk when they're
in process and they don't know who they
are and what they want to do
because it's i'm not there yet but not
knowing that
figuring it out is a [__] step in the
positive direction not in the negative
direction
right right yeah making that commitment
so
okay you think you gotta
you think you gotta like start with your
why then like you gotta just shift what
your why is who you are
you gotta yeah i know you have you have
a thing about starting with why
or about um your why i mean i think
a lot of us never even ask what our why
is we never ask ourselves what's our
vision like what do i want to do in life
you know i think
even that could spark that little voice
that spiritual voice and within each of
us
you know right no and that's crazy that
you say that as you guys were just
you know um we go ahead and go no but as
we uh
are going through the stuff that we're
doing man i was just thinking about
um who am i you know
who am i with all these titles right
i put title up at matthew and then you
got dad you got coach you got husband
you got father
you know you have um business owner
friend cousin
you know we have all these titles but
what if these titles were gone
right what if we didn't get called
cousin what if we didn't get caught
husband or whatever
and then and then you got the hobbies
basketball
you know uh camera all this different
stuff what if all that stuff was
stripped just like what this pandemic
put us in
what are we what are we if we can't go
back and do the things that we normally
do
and i feel like we have to go back to
what that is
and from what that is then that's where
we refrain
but if we're in fear like we're talking
about fear
uh uh the world is making me do this or
i'm a victim of this
then you're never gonna get to self
because now you have
and what if it's just like right here
you're right but in your mind
because the mind is dangerous it could
be good or it could be dangerous
in your mind you're just this this world
is just
crazy you're not you know so far away
like i'm never going to get there so
then it's like well i'll just continue
to keep doing what i'm doing but what if
it's just like saying no like it's like
a fast
let me like say today like i'm gonna
fast for my phone today whatever these
distractions are
i'm gonna fast my phone today um i'm not
going to
uh touch my camera i'm just going to
just
do nothing basically i feel like you've
you you get tested by things that
you have a pull to right so if
something's pulling you
even if you feel like it's positive like
you might want to find out what that
pull is
you know what i'm saying like i've
noticed lately for some reason that
i have this pulled of food like i'm like
why is that happening like i think and
what it is is because i know that i've
already dealt with other vices so i
don't want to go back to those
so when i get to a point where i'm
starting to feel anxious i'm like i'll
eat
but i know that i'm eating healthy food
so i justify it you know what i mean
what if it makes you feel good yeah
exactly so it's like
and it's it's crazy to think that
something and that's why
i think what's different about me is i
will question everything
and i think a lot of people don't
question [__] like who who
who's going to question a [__] uh
habit of eating broccoli and chicken
you know what i mean but why is it that
when i feel anxious i'm like
i'll eat like because it's a [__]
distraction
because the distraction is knowing that
this broccoli and chicken is good for me
so i'm distracted by a good feeling when
i was feeling an anxious feeling
and i like you know what i mean and
that's what i said i feel like that's
what makes
makes me makes me different and makes me
able to have conversations like this is
because
i'm [__] honest with myself who's
gonna say that like
no one's gonna come out and say oh yeah
i have an addiction to eating chicken
and broccoli or have a pulley
it's like no because that's healthy at
least it's better than mcdonald's at
least it's better than [__] whatever
everybody else is eating it's like
what's the idol yeah
and once you get rid of the idol you
know you show yourself right
but i really believe that it's the idol
bro
because same thing with basketball
basketball wasn't just having fun
that was daddy that was whatever my mind
wanted it to be
that was my counselor right right it's
like video games
they'd be in a whole nother world when
they do what they do
and then when you try to say hey johnny
johnny get up
they're like well but they you know it's
like it's like a drug
they react a certain way but but
emotions are crazy bro yeah and that's
what was
i had like i don't know if we talked
about it last time but i had
did i think we did i had like a moment
where i was like man
is that what he was talking about is
that the bike for me
and that's what was scary is because i'm
like i
like i'm like in my head i'm battling
because i'm like don't don't think that
like this bike is your life you know
what i mean
but i i really think that you know i did
some deep
digging i i talked to a counselor and i
was like hey you know
i you know i know what i like she wanted
to know what i do what my hobbies are
and all those kind of things and
she's like well you've been riding this
bike for you know however long you're
talking about thoughts of suicide
do you possibly think that your outer
actions are
matching you found something and the
reason that it feels
so good is because you're matching inner
feelings with outer action
because there's a possibility that i
could die on this thing yeah damn that's
deep
that's you know what i'm saying yeah and
so i actually was like
i i asked her that so i she
was just like we were just diving into
things and i i like had that thought and
i
she was like but who is it too though
and that's the thing
whoever that is and this is where i'm at
with the spiritual part
is we can't say like
it's just this one religion we're not in
control of that no
like like the more and more i'm reading
and stuff the more
i'm not even in control of myself even
when i feel like i'm not
like you know and it's and i feel like
that's what messes us up because we do
feel like we have control over our lives
but it's so deep bro like basketball was
my god
shoes was my god because it did
something to me in my emotions
but just because it made me feel good
doesn't mean it is good it's just like
that
everything has glitter and gold but
but now so now what's the difference
like now when you
when you when you're around basketball
when you're around shoes
how is it different now than it was
what's the feeling inside that gives you
so so for instance because the fight for
me was like
on tuesday people are the temptation is
matt play come on man we need you to
play no
matthew's a mentor and then matthew
wants to
be in your ear and matthew wants to pray
for you because nobody's going to do it
so in this atmosphere that we're trying
to change matthew has to have to
understand how the best self could
the best power is having self-control
and so
i feel like that's where when you do
find what you're supposed to be doing
it is in the back your mind is a
responsibility
and it trumps your feelings right so
it's
like now you have this like
it's almost like you don't have the
temptation as much
because you know that where you're
supposed to be spending your time and
how you're
supposed to be acting and that in itself
gives this responsibility and it makes
the decision easier
right you know what i'm saying but it's
crazy because you say that right
i feel like the reason why it's so like
long is because we're hard-headed it's
just like
because like for instance like when i
was doing this stuff
like i was losing myself because my mind
when i used to play it was like killer
be killed
and mentorship is out the window so if
you're losing a game or you drop a pass
or whatever
oh i'm on your [__] bro bro it's the end
of the world because the
y is still attached to that and the why
was
if i grind as hard as i can win every
game i'm gonna make it to make it to the
league and mom's gonna get off of
domestic violence
she's gonna have money like all this
lifestyle that if you make it it gives
you right
so that was still attached and then me
doing that a lot of kids didn't know me
but then this is where the humility part
comes from which i feel like we run from
is can you say a sorry when you really
did something wrong
and sorry doesn't mean saying hey i'm
sorry and then you do something again
no it's sorry to me it's like you're
hitting that reset button you analyze
what you did
you hold yourself accountable and then
you don't do it no more
and if you really care about that thing
you really do it it's just like with our
females
i guarantee you if we had a little
boo-boo and they felt that boo-boo and
they expressed to us in a way that we
understand i guarantee you we will
we will uh make that fix not 10 years
later because they'll be gone
instant and i be i feel i feel love does
that
when you love something truly you
wouldn't time
oh man i bought a meal on her this time
all right uh don't count the reps
right and i feel like we do that when we
don't really love what we love
but also too i feel like you can love
something
but be focused more on the result and
not the product
you understand what i mean so like when
you're playing basketball you're
only focused on the money you're only
focused on
because of the money is going to solve
all these problems but at the end of the
day
you're focused on money and you're not
focused on the product the product
if you were focused on the product you
would know all the things that you were
missing yeah you knew that the mind
wasn't right
right you knew that your grades weren't
right you knew that you were going to go
as far as you ah
well for me so my thing was because this
is how it trips you out
it's like you could say like with me was
like
okay i can't read but there's a solution
to that
because everything that i didn't do
there was a solution too
so with me like when i'm having these
performances 30 point games doing my
thing
i'm just now when i watch my highlight
tape like man
damn i couldn't i couldn't at least get
like
like a jc or we know but when i was
doing all this stuff in the process
i couldn't look at the results because
the result was
if i'm doing something right um
a college would be at my house and that
never happened so in my mind
so that's what i'm saying you were more
focused on the end but
the the product itself wasn't at the
forefront because then
i was up there yeah yeah but if you
would have fully defined the product
right with the mental game to go along
with that
that's where i feel like it would have
changed for you true and that's right
but this is where we
this is where i feel like people get
cheated on is
you can't expect somebody if we're if
we're created you got your mom and dad
and then they create you right
your teaching moments start at home
people try to hold people
people try to make people hold
themselves accountable when their [__]
is [__] up here
yeah like other people already got a
head start
but this this makes you basically
if it's right or wrong it's going to
give you your teaching of what society
is how it's supposed to work right
so like with me i was
feeling like a crackhead for a mentor
and that's what i felt
like i needed and i never got that and
then when i had it i tried to cling on
it like this is my dad
and then i'll get sean no he's not and
this is how he's not your dad
you're scoring all these touchdowns he
hugs you and makes you feel good but
when you're at
the nike and play store and all you
nieces lease
all you need is one pair of shoes and
you're just pushing the car and watching
the sun get loaded up
that was the moment for me to say that's
not my dad yeah where is my dad
so life speaks but are we listening you
know we don't need the
i think sometimes we try to make it
where it's like
[Music]
please speak to me but life is always
speaking
homeless people speak to me birds speak
to me consciousness no come on
it's literally just being conscious
we're and that's where i feel like
we're so we're so disconnected because
of all the [__] that we're
susceptible to on our phones and media
and all this other [__]
we're so disconnected from real life
yeah because we're missing all those
opportunities and all those little like
hints that the universe that
you know whoever out there is like
trying to tell you like like when you're
on your phone you walk right past that
homeless person who like
maybe you need to have a conversation
with that person exactly and that's why
i feel like if we're
if we're acting in our
gift and we're acting in our calling
we're aligned with
the [__] that we're supposed to see and
the stuff we're supposed to hear happens
if you're all [__] around not being
your best self and not
not acting in your highest potential you
miss those things
when you have your [__] head down
looking at your phone you might be
supposed to be meeting somebody that's
right next to you right right
when you're when you're like a bro and
that's what's been hard for me is i have
and i know everybody has got to be
spending way more time on their phone
during this pandemic because i was doing
research upon youtube and all
you're a doug though and i feel like
this is how i know like this is what
thugs do with certain things right if
you're a thug
you don't give a crap you're going to go
against you're going to go to the source
right
i feel like what makes us so creative
and what we do now
is we're not going to against the grain
we're just making venues
we're making functions right if we make
functions then you're able to create the
masses
but if this is the source right to of
communication
and then i go off and say something and
then it has to do with empowering people
then i cut off because i just gave my
whole script no
let's be subliminal and when you're
sublimable a subliminal about something
and then you like hey everybody's
getting free jordans now you have 20 000
people there
you might give two jordans away yeah but
then you had a message that was like
look at how many of you guys were slaves
to this
and you came but when i say hey who
wants a
you know a voucher for gap you know it
just depends on what it is yeah that's
like
they're accidentally feeding their ego
it's like they think that what they need
is those shoes
you know it's like somebody sold you
those shoes and it was crazy
but that's not preached to us and that's
why i feel like
conversations like this are so important
because
it it i had this when you have those
breakthroughs and you're like
why the [__] have i not been doing this
for so long bro people spend more money
on dumb [__] than they do on spending on
their self-development
like i bought i bought a
a coaching program i signed up with a
personal trainer like to everyone else
that's far-fetched like people spend
more money on their [__] car payment
than they spend on their
on their self-development and we wonder
why we're
depressed we wonder why we're anxious we
wonder why we're not happy
we wonder why we don't have the job or
the career that we want we wonder why we
don't have the relationship that we want
because we base it off of this like it's
like for if so
like for instance it's kind of like a
honeymoon stage you go on the honeymoon
stage and you're doing everything in
your power to show this person for the
first three months
that you're so loyal and once they say
i'm here there's a problem right you
people attach conditions
to whatever they're doing i'm willing to
do it if this this this line up but as
soon as it gets here i'm done
right and that includes your own
self-development which is where we fall
short
i'm willing to do i'm willing to be
better right but if it causes me
to not have a friday night out with with
the crew and i have to stay in and read
a book then there's a [__] problem
you know i mean it's fine right but if i
don't have money to go
out and because i feel like that's what
our age a lot of people are still
drinking and doing all that
that's fine but i'm not going to spend
i spent 750 dollars for a three-month uh
like mental coach program like
that's 750 dollars you know how many
drinks that is like do you not like
people are thinking that
it's too out the door to buy and i
always do this thing on my um
on my instagram like i'll make stories
and all my tick tock like
and it's that one e40 song everybody's
got choices right so i'll go in the
grocery store
and i'll put these things right i i can
buy a [__] whole entire bag of
broccoli that feeds me for the whole
week for four [__] dollars
and people spend three i think it was
or something on a little packet of
kitkats that's
crazy but it's far-fetched to buy the
broccoli
right it's far-fetched to buy the
chicken it's it but it's not
unreasonable to go out and spend a
hundred dollars on a meal it's not
unreasonable go out and tip your and and
i'm in the industry but i don't do it
anymore but it's not go
it's not far-fetched to people in the
industry that used to be me to tip 50-60
percent
it's like we're just throwing our money
away it's crazy but that's not
far-fetched but it's been 750
for three months right or to be in shape
be an athlete
performing at a level that i want to
perform it's far-fetched for me to get a
personal trainer because i feel like i
have more potential
i think that the reason why personal
growth or just
be having a growth mindset in general is
so
not a thing that anybody does unless
it's what i want to know what that is
that's why is it not sexy it's it's it
might even be as simple as like
as soon as you admit that you're doing
the personal growth thing as soon as you
admit that you just get a life coach
now you're now you just signaled to
everybody in your circle like i ain't
that great no no no that ain't that
great it's a personal thing that we
don't want to see
we want to see it within ourselves so
like the the people who take on personal
growth stuff the people who and
like absorb the tony robbins videos and
who watch this [__] and they try to like
make themselves better
that's like it's from the outside
circles of people who don't [__] with
that it's like a personality thing like
oh that's just kind of what they're into
like
i'm into my [__] i like to drink
whatever but like
what it really is is like this like
every single person regardless of where
you're at regards whatever [__] you do
what regards whatever your hobbies are
you should be into personal growth
and i think in our society doesn't it
right now like it's not
it's not cool it's just this other thing
over there that those [__] do
like i don't hike every day i
then people like insult themselves or
they're like i don't do that running
thing that ain't me like
but it's like no no that's for everybody
personal growth and like searching for
your spirit and your growth
is forever yes it's literally a one size
fits all
so how do we so so what happens in
society over the next let's say five
years it's craziest time right now but
like what happens to make us start
moving our brains towards this like
everybody gets personal growth like
personal growth as an individual is
almost a responsibility that everybody
should partake in you know it's not easy
but i think what needs to happen is the
people that are in
that are in in front of the lens need to
talk about the [__] more
because people have unhealthy
habits but everybody that's successful
to me that is is they might have a
drinking problem and they might but
they have some sort of principle that
has allowed them to get to where they
want to be
so those principles need to be shared
those like
if yeah you know they might somebody i'm
not trying to get to the bag but i'm
trying to get to the best version of my
brain and the best version of my mind
and the best version of positivity
if you can teach me how you got to to
get to there
you can teach me how to do that too so
that's what i feel like needs to be in
front of the lens is
what are these principles that are
making people
um go through the hard times right what
are the what are these principles that
are making people
um when doors get slammed they can walk
away and they have resilience and
they're like oh [__] i mean that's just
okay i'll do another one you know what i
mean i feel like it's
that's what needs to be important how do
you how do you maintain that how do you
maintain uh
persistence and and because that's what
personal growth is it's literally
persistence
it's a fight every single day it's a
fight
every single day and i feel like
everybody's is going to be different
and for me it's just i have to do
i find that when i'm it
it works for different people for
instance in my relationship okay my girl
is very
she has less of traits that i would say
that i have that are a little bit more
negative have a very addictive
personality like if i eat something i'll
eat it for the next year
if i get an energy drink i'm drinking
six like that's just how i am right
she has this like oh i can just have one
thing i'm like how do you do that
you know i can't does that [__] dude
yeah i can't do it i can't have this one
thing so my
i have this like for my personal growth
and for me
and for what works for me is this david
goggins like
thing i gotta do [__] that sucks but you
found that that's what works
and that's what i found that works for
me and and i have to get to the point
now
where now i feel like the cost of entry
to your business
the cost of entry to your podcast the
cost of entry to your personal growth
is listening to [__] people telling
you you're crazy like
why do i need to run every day and i'm
already in shape why
i because it makes me [__] feel good
i know how much i hate running and when
i go out there and say [__] you
i know that that's what i want i know i
want to be a bad [__] i just do
like and i think that's what bad
[__] do is they do [__] that
they don't want to do
like you it's not always going to be
great right you
to me it's a metaphor it's like i never
was a distance runner i started running
long distance why
because i've noticed in my life i always
start out strong and then i [__] fall
off
i can run 100 meters no problem right
and it's
and my thing is like because uh you know
the blue angels right
so blue angels are the professional uh
jet flyers that do the tricks right and
so my lady sent me this video on them
but this guy
was saying their turnover rate is not
you you sign up for a year you perform
for a year it's every event
so you can have a flight one event and
then not have a job the next right
and he was talking about this increase
in this performance
and when he was saying this stuff you're
thinking like yeah man you'll be like
killed or be killed
you know all this stuff and he said our
mindsets are
we're glad to be here and when i heard
that
i started going deep on like damn
it's actually really draining to keep
yourself
tooting the negativity to keep going but
when you
just i'm glad to be here it's like a
sense of peace
and then you just like like it's like a
hippie bro like
yeah gratitude is like a special thing
man
like it's like it's kind of like it got
magic powers in some ways man
and that's what i feel like too is i'm
like you know i've i've been
i've been in places where if i was in
those places before
i wouldn't be able to do the things that
i want to do now so that's where my
gratitude comes from
but i still have to have that i don't
know what it is i still have to have
bro i'll be i'll be outside in the
morning at like five o'clock when i go
out and run yelling at myself bro
because i feel like
who's gonna gash you up if you don't gas
yourself up you know what i mean
like you only get so much support
especially when you're acting in
something that people can't see
because we're in a point right now in
life where everything's about the flesh
and we can't see it it doesn't exist and
that's what it is
so if you're trying to do something that
people can't see
you're gonna get all that you're gonna
get you're not gonna get support from
bro i wish i had the support that i get
from my friends i wish i had that for my
family
like i really do but you can fix that
and you
want me to tell you how and this is just
real
so my dad passed away july 11th right
and um when he passed away i'm not gonna
lie to you
i was dealing with i can love you like
oh you need money
because there's no issue there's no hurt
right but with mom
dad brother sister there was some type
of form of hurt
and when you're hurt you kind of like
put up your armor right trust they just
break everything whatever those emotions
are
so when i got saved
it wasn't like i just went to church and
i got a bible now and i'm trying to read
every verse and then no i got saved
and then i got confronted with my issues
and i
finally had to deal with my issues and i
didn't understand
that first because i didn't have
mentorship
i'm in there like okay this pastor is
going to help me because every sermon he
talks about helping
i call he doesn't answer so then i'm
like
okay well what am i supposed to do i'm
back here fornicating with females
the old man still alive right so what i
realized was
how did i deal with it is i had to
figure out
where i'm really hurting and where i was
really hurting was
when dad was with me he was abusive and
the mom finally got the
courage to leave him she left him and
then sophomore year he came
and then i had some money in coming in
and then dad
took that money you know bamboozled me
got trust from my brother
took that money when i wanted to play
basketball if i had this money i could
make it get to a camp
and then when i got saved he comes in
and it was just like
don't even just stop whatever you
are going to say about what you've done
it's okay
i forgive you but then in that forgiving
there was still more still more of the
process
the process was how do you have
confession with your truth with your
hurt
with people that hurt you sometimes we
try to do is like people hurt us and
then we just go like this
and then as soon as the relation gets
rocky it comes out
[__] you like we just lose it right
out of control so i had that moment with
my dad
but then in that moment with him he had
a moment with understanding like son
i went through the same thing so now
we're more alike than different
which we all are no so so that's what
i'm so that's the [__] that's going
on right now
is that we're all i was telling him this
the other day
life right father abuse
mother alcoholic father abuse right
certain things that i was missing in my
life
uh all three of us okay asian black
white
all thought about committing suicide
life will [__] you up
life can [__] you and it just takes no
[__]
it takes nobody and it can
it it will literally beat you to your
[__] knees and spare
not one single person it will convince
you that you deserve it too easy
that you [__] deserve it okay but we
all want to be divided
we all want to talk [__] we all want to
argue we all want to be separated if you
don't believe this and [__] you
i heard something the other day because
that's what we asked
i heard something the other day it blew
my mind and said we all should act
and we should all give the grace that we
need for ourselves
people are out here talking [__] that
aren't even happy people out here
talking [__] that their family's [__]
falling apart
you have other things that you need to
be focused focus on your [__] self
don't focus on other people don't focus
on what people are posting
bro i literally i thank god that i've
gotten control of this but i
have not [__] argued about racism
or politics i've had conversations but i
have not argued with not one person this
whole entire time because i [__]
won't do it i'm not gonna sit here and
argue with you on [__] facebook and
instagram i won't
i've had every time someone says
something negative me i [__] block
them that's it
you don't like what i post go [__]
yourself that's it because it's
people aren't acting in the grace that
they need i need grace
because i'm not perfect but everybody
that has judgments that
that base it and and says that you're
you're wrong you're this you're racist
you
you don't care about this it's like bro
why does that i guess the reason that i
don't have a super strong opinion about
all this is because
i'm we're humans like
whether whether how you believe how we
got here
if you [__] sit back for a second and
think about how we got here how is that
not a [__] magical thing
where the [__] did we come from nobody
knows it only is based upon what you
believe in something you can't see
nobody knows how the [__] we got here
we're still worried about what
people what [__] color people are
that's so
[__] stupid to me and so surface
level that we're concerned
about [__] somebody's skin color
whether
i just it blows my [__] mind it blows
my mind but just like that because
i felt like through these tragic
tragedies that we had
it was an opportunity to like listen to
understand
and there was a time where you know my
sister that i call my sister she is
white
but she's seeing this stuff and then you
ain't posting this no you're considered
racist and she opened up to me and she
said matt i don't understand
but what i understand is there is a time
in our era
where out of fear people
put this like painted this picture yeah
and it was because they're
yeah like yeah and like when we do this
stuff
it's just something how we act but
that's why like with myself
i know like if i'm acting i guess like
uh
like like with my emotions when i'm
frustrated or angry
i isolate i isolate because i know
what's going to come out
it's not going to be good so the people
around me don't deserve that but
i can't give what i don't have and i
can't
expect people to do what i'm not willing
to do
so i can't say give me love but i don't
give you love
and i think that's what our issue is is
we want people to
do something with this thing i'm talking
about right now i'm changing my whole
perspective
my sit like i said before like my sister
you know she's going through some things
but i'm judging her by her past
not because i don't i don't feel her
hurt is because i'm hurt
so then i don't trust that because now
it's like well i want to give her
but i'm a judge her because she was this
prostitute or she has it but
i'm forgetting that no before she was a
prostitute actually she got herself her
innocence taken from her she was raped
but what we do is we want to forget
that and then now she is moving in her
choice but the way she's moving in her
choice
is a way that she was taught when she
didn't have a choice yeah
so then so then the reason that you have
that mindset is because you're judging
and that's what that's what's going on
so you judge her for your choices
so people judge other people for their
choices
and how they respond or how they post or
how they react or why they're not
protesting it's like
yo like did we not forget that
chronovirus is happening like and people
are pissed off that people aren't going
downtown
people are upset because people aren't
protesting it's like bro somebody asked
me why i wasn't protesting i said
because i got a [__] baby on the way
i'm not about to catch a charge or catch
a [__] bullet
or catch a [__] something in my head
you don't really need to give answers on
that [__] yeah and that's
and that's what i'm saying but that's
the whole point is like people
out here are like you must be racist
because you're not
and that's what and that's what i and
that's what is and then don't that piss
you off though
like when somebody tells you something
that you're not
the instant the the quickest
emotion right and that definitely i
don't know about you but my old
defending self is i'm knocking heads
and then now because if you knock heads
you get a charge
i'm pissed but i isolate but i feel like
well what's the right solution the right
solution is
do what you want treat your neighbor how
you want to treat yourself
love your neighbor like how you love
yourself because that's the best way
it's the hardest way
it's hard because we have all these
judgments you've got to do what's hard
dude people have been taking the easy
way people
it's easy to get mad it's easy to get
pissed off but like
that's as a society we all got to stop
doing it and that kind of matches up
with what i was talking about about the
grit
because it's like you have to do the
[__] hard [__] and
and for some people most people
honestly that's that inner battle i just
think that no one talks
in a way that i talk like [__] that i
don't i can't think that like
there's nothing about taking the hard
way out that doesn't require a little
grit
that doesn't require a little edge you
know what i'm saying like no [__] that
like no [__] that and that's what when
you were talking about how
love your neighbor as you love yourself
people don't love themselves and so
that's
why it's so easy for people to treat
people like [__]
and that's what people don't understand
is that you're in your head talking so
bad to yourself all day
and this is the most important right
matthew to matt
is the most important jake the jake is
the most important nate to nate is the
most important
so if i can call myself a piece of [__]
why the [__] can i call you a piece of
[__]
how much how easy is that right it's so
easy and it doesn't reflect off of me
because i'm already feeling that
and so that's why i tell people but how
do you don't worry about what
huh how do you change the game i
personally think
is the only reason i have the i have a
hard line for myself because
i like to um one of my um
things is is for my brand is is uh
actin i'm sorry inspired by action okay
so the podcast and the speaking and all
that kind of stuff i do have to talk
about it
but i would rather be about it but i
know that if i don't talk about it
i'm doing people around me and people
that want to hear me talk and want to
hear me speak and want to hear what i
have to say in injustice
because i do have i do have a crowd i do
have a voice right everybody does
but i would rather see people do like
you know i had to have this conversation
with my girl like
where do we and that's what i feel like
is most important is that circle
like start with your [__] self but
nobody does that okay
because it's it's it's a distraction i
can get up as soon as i get up
i'm already pissed off but guess what i
can go seek that so then i can't
i can tell my partner that john jacob
jingleheimersmith pissed me off on
facebook
and that's why i'm mad not because i'm
unhappy with myself
disappointment is what people don't get
is that like you said life is always
talking we're not listening
disappointment is your guideline
for everything if you're disappointing
yourself stop making
decisions that are disappointing and
then you don't have those feelings right
so start it starts here i like i said i
was having that conversation my girl how
do we
feel about this how do we feel about
what happened okay
because there's no [__] doubt in my
mind and there's no question
that what happened was wrong hundred
percent he [__] kneeled on that man's
neck
for eight minutes he [__] murdered
him he did not detain him he [__]
murdered him
was that an act of of racial
um hate crime i don't know
i'm not an investigator and that's what
i think shitty is that me saying i don't
know some people will call me racist
but i'm not there i'm not there we don't
what what what's hard for me is that we
don't ever get the full story
that's why i don't have a passionate
view towards this issue
because the information that everybody's
getting
i don't know if it's ever full the full
story right
you never do it and you never will never
this whole thing is just so messy as we
all think we're like this is exactly
what happened
exactly none of it it's all just like a
wheel so all of these cases
have things pop up things hidden it's
about
money stuff can [__] happen or stuff
can disappear
if it's paid for people forget that [__]
people forget you know we're we're like
we we say that the media
um everybody is such a fan of saying
that the media skews things right
the media is your phone so people think
that it's not skewed on instagram but
they think it's skewed on cnn or fox or
whatever [__] i don't i don't watch
tv okay
why are we so blind to that whatever is
being talked about
your viewpoint matt on on today's racism
and coronavirus
whatever you actually think and whatever
you're spoken is going to pop up on your
phone
if you think that this is what it does
because that's what i'm saying if you
think
if you think that this is all 100 that
there's systematic racism
that that blah blah blah blah blah those
articles pop up on your phone
and this is not my viewpoint but i if i
think that all that [__] doesn't
exist and blah blah blah blah
my issues and my standpoints pop up on
my phone they get posted
you post yours and then we [__] argue
it's division and that's the point
and i keep skipping over what me and my
girl but we had this conversation right
how do we feel how do we act what are we
gonna do
my girl was like i don't really feel
comfortable
posting things but and she's
and i believe every word that comes out
of her mouth that she said that this is
what we do and i sometimes i let her
lead because i'm like okay
what are you comfortable with what are
you okay with if that situation happens
i sat down with her and i said what do
we do
because people want to know what we
represent people everybody wants to know
what are you doing in your [__] house
what are you doing over here
you don't let that happen if you have to
give up your own freedom you do that
you don't let that happen you don't sit
there and [__] record this man
killing this guy
you you act and you do something about
it so that's our standpoint
for anybody that needs to know and
nobody needs to [__] know because
that's where i know and that's why
i people sitting back think they're
getting [__] support by someone
posting something that's not gonna do
[__]
it's literally not gonna do [__] it's
not bro i
i think that all of us don't fully
understand what social media is
no like bro it's just something that
when we were in high school
like of course you got it because that's
what everybody did you never questioned
like wait i ain't gonna get it like it's
like
like if your parents let you have it
quote unquote when it first came around
then that's
you have it and like we didn't we didn't
realize i don't think we're realizing
how much it affects our psychology as a
society like our
our entire planet consciousness is
affected hardcore by
media and news and all the social media
and it just takes that extra like having
those conversations like wait
what's really going on like if we were
in this situation what was going on like
we've got to
set down the phones and be like all
right wait and have those conversations
yeah yeah so like him and i have
great conversations about this and
sometimes we view things differently
and we don't hate each other he's my
best friend so
the conversation why the [__] how is it
like
why is that not allowed why is it not
allowed for people to have different
views why is this
people get offended and that's the
that's where i say that we're soft
and that's what i'm saying they were
successful but this is where i would
disagree is
like like we say this at our house
feelings
feelings matter but they're not facts
and so
jake who am i to say you feel a certain
way strong about something
if i come in and be like yo you're a
[__] for that
you're going to be like i don't even
know you
you're going to get offended and i feel
like
and that's just like when like you see
people in gangs i can't go into
a gang environment and be like uh you
don't know that
uh why are you banging over you know a
rag that you you know
it's dumb it's ignorant right if i do
that though
even though that might be right factual
like
you don't have no stocks on that
concrete like
i'm going against their belief and their
belief is like
you don't even know what we represent
you ain't never asked you ain't
interviewed you ain't slept here you
don't know what
for one gangs structure is a family
model
that's their model they've got more
community than a lot of us
come on but see that's our issue is i'm
at the point where we have to stop
talking and start
acting that's so that's what that was
like we got to [__] the talking now
we've been talking for years 400 years
10 and a year
but we need to be about action and then
what's so crazy about it is like just
like with the event we did
40 kids off of word of mouth but imagine
if we're more consistent
imagine if we start adding to that well
how do you add to that matt
you need a dj we need all that bro no
for real
let's add to it yeah no but because now
now we're slapping tunes
now we're playing music now it's a
different vibe what i'm gonna do and
this is just my devotion
i can't probably get 10 pairs of shoes
but i'm trying to ask people and then
i'm going to get a pair of shoes
so then in that i'm just blessing but
they're going to be like why are you
blessing
because god did it for me i just want to
love all people
so then now that's changing the
narrative because if i'm trying to go
against drake drake is making them feel
a certain way
and i just go and say hey you're living
wrong
drake is still making them feel a
certain way and i can give you truth and
everything but what are you giving me
beyond that
see the devil give you a false lie and
an item why did you do a word with
nothing
and say figure it out that's backwards
no i want to give you
some truth and then up here's an item
and then here's a process walking with
you just like when my daughter rode her
bike
i didn't say oh i'm not an active i'm
not i mean i'm not a dad that's not a
deadbeat dad so i was there we had a
date to ride that bike
she wanted to ride the bike earlier she
said i'm ready to actually ride my bike
and then now we started the process of
riding that bike that process took two
days but in that process
i had to let go she had to let go she
asked for help
i asked for help i had to accept that
she said daddy i got this and then she
fall
i'm a big girl but i had to do all these
things that were so like
it's okay oh no baby you'll be okay it's
like being crazy if you're
not yeah but you're guiding her right
and i think when we go through so much
things
it's kind of like here's the seed but
i can't give you else here's the sea
throw and you figure it out i don't
think that that's the best way
it's like here's a seat and i'm going to
show you
and then i'm not going to leave you but
i'm allow you to start
learning how to do these things with
your own self but then i don't
disconnect from you
you're a phone call way you're you know
one drive away and then up
you did this right but just remember
like you're doing videos with me
you don't cut me off it doesn't get
frustrating sometimes
my process my process is like aol it's
not 5g or
whatever this stuff is but i'm not done
but i'm gonna get it
but because you don't quit on me i'm
getting a little bit better because of
you're still guiding me through this
process
we like to control the process and if
it's not fast like me then
they're not gonna figure it out that's
just like getting somebody saved
they're going through a onion like
you're peeling an onion back
who am i to be like get it right now and
then cut you
we can't do that yes this studio was not
built overnight like
that's what i but that's what i feel
like that's what i feel like is
happening right now is everybody's
acting as if
you i'm gonna send you an article that
needs to change your mind
and that's it that's it right there it
goes in with the if you if you're not
this then you're that like do you like
this thing or do you like this thing
it's like well i don't really like why
do i have to choose one of those
it's like a q test being [__]
multiple choices and that's what i'm so
i had i had
i had a i had a conversation with
somebody that
that i said i'm not taking i'm not
picking aside
you're not going to get me to pick a
side of i either think that there's
systematic racism or i think there's not
i'm going to stand right in the middle
because if i don't stand right in the
middle then i have all this pull from
each side
my goal for myself is
to bring everybody together through this
self-development journey
the self-development journey to me is
what brings everybody together because
the reason i feel like we judge people
so much is because and we lack empathy
empathy is what makes us figure out that
we're more alike than we are different
because if you've been punched in the
mouth if you've been kicked in the nuts
by life okay
if you haven't dealt with that [__] and
know how [__] hard it is you will
look at your person
and somebody next to you and go i know
exactly how i felt when i was battling
thoughts of suicide
jake did the same thing we've had
like maybe six deep conversations that
we've known each other for
15 years and i are i have so much
empathy for you and i have so much
respect for you because of that i don't
give a [__] what you believe about all
this you're still my homie
because of that but we don't do that
okay
people don't go through those processes
of fixing themselves
finding out where they're lacking
finding out because you can only judge
when you think you're perfect
but if you know you're not perfect you
don't judge that's why i don't judge
people for
and honestly i i have that you know that
that
go big or go home do it all or do it or
don't do it at all
mentality i respect the people i really
do
that have been down there for the last
four months [__]
yes do it then if you're gonna [__]
do it then do it
you have my respect but do i necessarily
agree no
you know what i mean but we judge
because
we don't again we don't have that
peace within ourselves we do we are not
a judgment-free form from ourselves
like you know i talk to my girl and
sometimes we get in arguments because we
don't
you know we're not i'm very punctual
because that's what works for me
right if i don't have a schedule i'm all
over the place i get anxiety i'll start
doing weird [__] i'll start eating i'll
start drinking caffeine like i just
that's just how i get down
she can be more free so when i say
we're [__] late let's go she says
nate don't you think i judge myself
enough and i'm in my head going
i do the same damn thing i wake up and
i'm like god i should have got up
earlier right away
even at 5am like you know i'm sure there
was somebody else out running right now
we're at 4 30. yeah i can't function
like that i'm like i'm sorry
i did not i don't bro i don't know why
you found what works for you yeah
but that's not healthy but what i'm
saying is is i get
is when she said that to me it woke me
up because i was like bro you do that
same damn thing the second you open your
eyes
the second you open your eyes you're
judging yourself and now i'm putting
pressure on her
because she's not ready she's [__]
pregnant she's so
she's [__] subconsciously growing a
[__] human being and i'm like we're
late
you have to we we have to stop and pee
again like
and i'm like when you get those
awakening moments
is because you're trying to become at
peace with yourself but when people
aren't at peace with themselves when
they're in
an offense instead of there's no offense
there's no defense when you're in
right in the middle in consciousness
right that's when you're opening those
things
but if i'm attacking if i'm an offense
on her i'm like no we're [__] late i
don't care what you're
saying and she turns around and says
nate
don't you think i judge myself enough
and i'm like damn
right but that's no we're not doing that
right now right
we're uh we're off you don't believe
this you don't believe that well
no i posted it i posted you didn't see
you i'ma send it to you i archived it
like
no no don't judge me don't judge me
these people that are judging
they're on offense and they're not
seeing where they judge themselves
and they're not seeing where they're
unhappy with themselves so that's why
it's so
easy to place it on somebody else
because you are
your body your mind is the [__] and
most important part
and that's the temple so this if you are
destroying yourself
what makes it so easy you can't destroy
somebody else
you're going to exactly that you're
going to even if you
even if you say you're not and that's
where i feel like
for us we we were
bad in relationships right we were we
hurt other people because
we were out for what was best for us and
we're on offense
i have a need i have an insecurity
i have a uh um a need for
what's another word for need or
insecurity whatever those negative
things are
and i'm on offense i gotta get that
that's that's what's that's what's on my
mind that's what's on the front of my
mind that's what's in my subconscious
i'm getting it at the cost of anybody
that's what it is i have a need to
spread my thoughts i have a need to
spread my
this word that i have and it's at the
cost of [__] anybody i'll tear you
apart
and that's what's going on right now man
there's no open conversations happen
i've had two open conversations out of
all the conversations i have
during all this [__] all this
coronavirus [__]
all this the protests and all that kind
of stuff
i have had two open conversations the
rest have been [__] you
go [__] yourself see see i i think right
there
that cornerstone right there that's
where like the [__] who
are controlling the puppets you know the
puppeteers that's where they're winning
is they're taking away our ability to
have a conversation
we can't we can't control our emotions
and we can't regulate like our
uh you know we can't we can't realize
that we're not our thoughts we can't sit
there and have
like these open conversations and so
what what happens instead is like we get
keyboard warriors and we get
like oh i'm going to take 30 minutes to
respond to this person and they're going
to know exactly what's up but it's like
how many it's not real conversation bro
you miss out on all this eye contact you
miss out on this authenticity you miss
out on
remembering that they're a real human
being and they got their [__] like
by someone saying i got all this blah
blah blah they're not saying also i
think that i'm perfect
like but we think that they are saying
that and they think that we're thinking
that we're perfect
we're we're we're caught up in this [__]
and we're not even able to have
conversations about it and that's what
it bums me out it really does don't you
guys see what's happening there
they're making us mad so we can't talk
about this [__] bro right like that's
now you got a corona virus that's
telling you where madison be six feet
or stay at home so now if you're doing
that right
and now you're already isolating
yourself
and then what are you watching
television
and then if you're doing money more
money and then if you're watching
television or
frustrated whatever man it's it's ugly
and if you're not allowed to go outside
then you get unhealthy
right but the blood pressure medication
all the time i just
i just this eyebrow like i said it goes
through that being radical
yeah you know i just think that there's
to to be honest i
i don't think things happen by accident
like so if you start to understand one
thing i feel like you start to
understand everything right so i started
for instance for me you know me with the
cameras right
i started to realize and with phones
okay
let's just use phones for instance
because everybody has an iphone okay
[Music]
the the stuff and the features and all
the things that are going on
with the phone that you have now were
purposely left out for the next one
right cameras it's the same thing the
stuff that they didn't put on this
camera
they knew because they're already
planning that [__] so far out
that's what the [__] is happening right
now that's literally what's happening
right now
this shit's all a [__] plan like do
we not think it's a coincidence that
there's all these conspiracies going on
and all these people are getting caught
up in like sex
trafficking and all this [__] i don't i
don't like to talk and
i'm a conspiracy i don't like to talk
conspiracy though because i think it's
so
people judge so harsh that it's just
like there's no conversations to be had
but
i think this shit's all a plan there's
been there's been things where people
have slipped up
they have [__] lied you can't lie and
expect
your people to trust you they and that's
where i drew the line at this whole
coronavirus [__]
is they went on and said it's not
necessary to wear a mask
the first couple days right and then
they went on and said
we lied about that that's obviously not
their words this
tony fauci guy who's supposed to be the
scientist behind all this [__]
says we knew that there would be a
shortage of masks
for hospitals so we told that's why we
told you bro
tell the [__] truth people respect
the truth now we don't know what to
believe now that's where i literally
they like it bad dude that situation
right there that was bad that's what i'm
saying
now you have lost trust and now to me
i'm like oh [__]
this to me i'm like okay man this
thing's really out here killing people
then you see that now i'm like i don't
believe a [__] word that's coming out
of your mouth now let me ask you guys
this though cause this is what i was
thinking out of all this stuff that's
going on
my thing that i think about is are you
really
ready to die for your cause that's all i
think about exactly
and then when you're talking about the
titanic thing if we gonna die
we're gonna die you can't like i'm not a
billionaire to pay and whatever
so we're all on the same playing field
yeah
but are we really at this stage of my
life
ready to die for the cause so that's
where i feel like that
this whole metaphor comes in if you are
sick you're going to be around sick
people
and i mean that in every every sense of
the
of the word right it bro if you're
aligned if you're going where you're
supposed to be going
you're gonna [__] miss coronavirus
bro it's not i don't care what anybody
thinks
this [__] is all pre-planned and i i
mean your life i don't mean all this
conspiracy [__] i mean your life
if you're on the path that you're
supposed to be taking if you're acting
in your higher self
you miss all that [__] you don't get
around it
into it man if i'm not on this spiritual
journey if i'm not on this personal
development journey i don't meet matt i
don't meet you
i don't meet the people that are
influential in my life i don't see the
things that i need to see
i don't listen to the podcast that made
me sign up for this dude's
personal development thing i don't see
like it just
it doesn't happen so that's what i'm
saying is if you're sick
you're going to be around sick people
and i mean that every possible way
you could be sick in the mind that's
what i'm saying and then physically
mentally
spiritually financially so that's why
right
to me that's what that's what i was
talking about right if you're if you're
sick you're going to be around sick
people and i mean that in this [__]
right now
and i mean that when when this shit's
not going on you're going to be around
toxic people
i just i don't i have already said i
told my girl
there's a there's a um there's a little
um
there's a fine print and the mask
wearing if you're hard of hearing
or if you're deaf you don't have to wear
one that means i don't have to wear one
okay
and that's what i tell people when i
walk in i already told my girl listen
this helmet go out that's how i'm gonna
go out that's it
i've already accepted it i'm not gonna
get it i'm not going to
i just don't believe that faith but if i
do but check this out if i do [__]
get it i know that i'm healthy enough
i'm not gonna die there's one but so
they'll tell us
we're a [__] mask because this is
what's going to prevent you but they
don't tell us how to build our immune
system yeah you know why don't work out
dude go work out
go outside meditate guess what you know
why
because that takes money away healthy
people take money away from the [__]
elite that's just what it is
well okay all right so let's use this
analogy i feel like we're back on the
titanic and essentially the intercom kit
we're all just employees we're there
like we're on
we're we're people on the ship and then
they come on the intercom
and we're all good we're on the titanic
we're floating along there's no iceberg
and then they say hey
the people around you are your [__]
enemies you got to get your gun out and
shoot at them
and all of a sudden we're running around
shooting our lasers and our guns at each
other
and we're dodging it but we're hitting
the ship and we're making our own
[__] holes
and then none of us have stopped and
been like wait hold up who was the guy
on the announcement like wait what did
you actually do that i'm not supposed to
like
like we're we're destroying the own our
own ship and i feel like it's
it's it sucks because we you know so
many people kind of come to the
conclusion of like brilliant they're
telling they're lying to us
and they're trying to make us mad and
like so many of us are pretty much at
this point where it's like we
like we see that we're getting kind of
brainwashed here
but now what is the thing like now what
like what can we do
and i think the the biggest answer is
literally kind of like
this self-development like you gotta
look at yourself
you know look at yourself like jordan
peterson for example like i sort of
stumble upon his videos and he talks
about like
he was he was kind of like the father i
never had on youtube i was like
i was like oh man he's like inspiring me
like tell like you know
work on myself and like look at these
things and look at my thoughts and
and these sort of things i mean i i
think that we get so caught up in these
conversations and they
they we the place that i find myself
with the with the conversations it's
good to have him but then at the end
it's like [__] this sucks man yeah i
guess we just gotta wait for what's next
and you sit back and you see
and it's like i and i'm not saying that
there is an answer and i'm not saying
that i have an answer but i'm saying
like
okay we are at the edge of this
conversation what could we do
like what's what's a thought experiment
we could bring in like what
i mean it just seems like this is like
the one answer that comes across so yeah
and that's what uh so what we're talking
about in the beginning i feel like this
is how it starts
but we we i just feel like we don't have
the power
no but no but see that's where the
spiritual comes to me
yes i agree with some power though yeah
we do so we do have power but i just
feel like we're up against
some things that we don't even [__]
know because but there's more consumers
there's more consumers than they are
with the people that are running it
but but listen to this as a human and
you know this 100 percent you
know that whatever you believe so
i i personally will listen to you talk
right
because i know that we think similar
okay i know that
i will listen to you talk but if we have
a belief
that the whoever is controlling what
what's going on in the media
they they they're tapped in they're
tapped in so
they know what you think and they're
gonna feed you that information so
you're not gonna listen to me or you or
jake you're gonna listen to them because
that's what that's what they think
this is the thing though and this is
what they we have to understand
is they're not in control of the
spiritual
so yeah they may say something
but spiritual was deeper than yeah it's
just deeper
it's so much deeper that i do know but
but you have
people that's why bro that's why they
call it the one percent
true and they're running the [__] but
this is the no but what i'm saying is
there's people
even in self-development so there is
more
bro there's let's just say the 95
percent
there's five percent of people that
really want to [__] that really want
to do this
that really are willing to go deeper
that really
really are willing to look at themselves
and go where
where am i not being my best self bro
but the easiest thing
is we're just looking to survive and
survival means
that we take whatever will come at us so
if
i'm not gonna go out and search
something if i have to go out and say
let me find a great [__] podcast or
let me turn on netflix what am i gonna
do
then netflix takes less time and less
effort
if they're gonna feed you information
you're gonna take it it's free food bro
it's free food it's it's it's a free
diet
it's appetizing for what you think and
it's appetizing for the brain wash
that's already been going on
it feeds it it feeds it and it feeds it
and it feeds it
that's something that i just feel like
at this point that i'm not saying i'm
gonna stop because i'm not gonna stop
but like you said we're up against
something that we didn't even know about
we we we don't we don't know about it we
don't know how powerful
but but i think when we get to this like
humbling like it's not even it's almost
taking the word humble out of our mouth
but it's kind of like this like
all right [__] we're pretty defensive
what can we do though we just keep going
yeah exactly
so all right so how do we anybody listen
and how can we
if they've never experienced
spirituality or like any sort of like
that soul feeling how do we spark that
and then people who have
how do we give them some advice to like
sharpen that [__]
like how do we get people to like
because we we can stand all day and say
this sucks and we have no [__]
control over that thing over there
eventually you got to like start
sitting down and like digging or doing
yeah planting some seeds or something so
so so what can anybody do to like
sharpen their spiritual side like
in a time like right now well i'm just
like even like right now i believe that
right now we're booming these tuesdays
out and tuesday we were at new heights
and basically what we did is um i felt
led to
lord's gym is closed and that's where
our functions used to be it's a church
i'm kind of weirded out by if we're
believing in this higher power
why the hell are we just following these
like you know the government like a
little sheep
you know and so i felt like god was
dealing with me like just do it i was
thinking
a little bit oh i was like you know he's
just like just do it just do it just do
it and so
um in doing that i knew that it wasn't
just about me
and doing that it was like make the post
but in that post pastor mike's wife made
the flyer and then in another post with
that flyer
who are we gonna hit up who are all the
uh videographers
photographers that we can in vancouver
nate on there whatever
i'm having dudes like who's gonna be
there it's not about who's gonna be
there there's an opportunity for you to
uh create you know growing your craft
and then i feel like this is what
happens with certain people
people are still chasing money and not
love [__] the money
because it's gonna be god or money at
the end of the day forget all that
god is love so why don't we just chase
love and in love the bag follows
but what we have to understand in that
is nate showed up
they didn't ask for a penny nate ain't
never asked for a penny for me
you know what our thing is if i'm going
somewhere you're coming with me
and then now that i'm making a little
bit money
hey how much do i charge to do this i'll
pay you
not because he needs the money it's
because i want to bless him
for his creativity because i don't want
him as valuable as he
is i don't want him to be hung up on a
nine to five
and that nine to five he's taking so
much time
so much of his time and then he's tired
to do what he loves
and even if he doesn't love it it's
still a it's a tool that he can utilize
that most people can't do
to get him where he needs to go and not
let's get a mansion no let's just be
let's just sustain
yeah i feel like by like by following
your bliss you can bring other people on
and give them kind of a scaffolding
right like the platform that's the point
you know platform
that's the point is that that i was
talking about earlier nobody wants to
give the game out
like the game is whatever you possess
that can help somebody is is that's and
that's what i what i told him
is that's what i feel like
having not doing things on your own is
is giving the game out
right so him and i or we're in like this
this partnership like i i like and we
don't have
contracts we don't have this we don't
have that we don't have to mess this
stuff up that's what it's like
we don't have this [__] it's like i
i own you contracts yeah it's like
it's like bro i believe in his bro i
believe in his
like i i believe in his vision like i'm
like dude this [__]
works bro this [__] works and what's
crazy is that
you have somebody like him that and this
is how
this is why what makes matt different is
bro i've been hustled before
i've been worked for people that i was
like okay i'm gonna do videography like
bro they're gonna put me on full time
like you know other [__]
they want to film seven five seven days
a week and have edits pumped out every
day and pay three thousand dollars a
month
are you [__] kidding me bro that's
they're like but you're shooting for
four hours bro that's an hour drive time
four hours on location every [__] day
that's like
editing takes longer and and exactly and
it's like bro you have people that
and that's why i talked to him is that
people out here trying to pimp people
and and people fall to it because they
don't know their value
like i would rather honestly i would
rather give somebody like him someone i
believe in i believe in his vision it
goes to a cause
for [__] freezing get paid then get
paid and get pumped
and get paid and get pimped i looked at
a job the other day jake you would not
believe this
i'm like okay this [__] i gotta go back
to work right
maybe i'll go back and be a videographer
because that's what i really love to do
okay
i know that the page is not gonna be as
good as freelance i know it's gonna be
as i'm
building my business right now but i'm
gonna go back and do something
they had a job posted and this is i just
wanna
i don't judge anybody for working at
nine to five i just to wake people up
like this job these are the requirements
so it's for a real estate firm i'm doing
real estate content right now so i was
like okay perfect right
build the resume i'll do my gigs on the
side it's perfect right
videography photography two positions
um manage all social media that's a
marketing person
um make flyers graphic design and
um one other thing um
coordinate uh something else that's
um coordinate like shoots and all that
kind of [__] that's like
these are separate jobs they're saying
this is all part of your job this is all
part of your [__] job you know what
the salary was
forty thousand dollars a year and and
what makes me sad
is is is again i'm not this is not a
judgment i don't want people to think
this is a judgment
somebody will [__] take that because
they think that's what they're worth
i went on there and i was like you know
i'm gonna apply to this [__] job
because i did and i'm gonna wait for
them to call me back
and i'm going to go in there knowing
that i'm going to negotiate this i'm not
taking that if you don't
so i looked up all the different
salaries for that
in america your average videographer
makes
around 55 000 a year your average
photographer
50 your average marketing person 50 your
average graphic design
50. add that [__] up
and somebody will take that and and and
and then what i don't like about it is
that somebody that has great talent
will take that and then resent the craft
they'll take that [__] [__] videography
[__] this i can't do this anymore i
can't do this [__] that happened to me
i was getting overworked and underpaid
you have to value your craft and
what you're doing and like i said what i
like so much about matt
is that and what's crazy to me is i i
had this
he said this to me and i was like bro
because at this point like we're
i feel like we're just now like really
really really digging into our
friendship and really getting to know
each other
like this last year we would like just
do jobs every once in a while like he
hit me up hey can you feel for me yeah
you know this for you can you do this
for me kind of thing right
he hit me up bro and was like i'm
applying for a grant
for my program if i was to hire you full
time
how much money would you need to make
and i was like
i was scared because i was like i don't
wanna but this is how much he's asking
me honestly i was honest with him i said
75 g's a year and
and that would be me working for you
full-time but still able to do my
my own stuff because he would never take
that from me he said i'm going to ask
for that
like i was like are you [__] kidding
me
this is how it should go that's what i
but but it's so mind-blowing because
i've never had an experience like that
i've never had someone
believe in me that much he lit it was no
question
it wasn't like this oh no can we
negotiate that
dude i'm like that's a that's 75 grand
that's a lot of money
do you know that's like 7 000 a month
like do you know that nate like
there was no [__] negotiation he said
all right i'm gonna ask for that in my
grant
i need to i need someone to make content
i want to pump my content all the time
he needs he needs to run the business
now he's
a he is what that job requires what that
job is asking for he's a photographer
he's a videographer he creates his own
content he does his website
he makes posters he does [__] he he
shouldn't be doing that
but guess what because of people that
are selfish and because people
don't want to build a team and they want
to do everything themselves and they
want to give credit to anybody else but
they don't want to be the bulls you know
that's what i'm saying
they they won't do that so i can already
fill one of his gaps before he can pay
me
believing that one day it will come and
then all these things start falling into
place and then he sees the loyalty
and then there's no question because i
know that this program
bro this [__] program is so fire like
i
i really like it it blows my mind that
and and
and that's what that nobody has picked
it up and nobody has
we don't have these contracts yet and
and because what i firmly believe and
what i tell him
is that because it's gonna be huge
like nobody's donated two thousand
dollars yet because this isn't a two
thousand dollar program
you know what i mean nobody's like oh
hey yeah matt i want to support i'm
gonna give you 500
for the year it's like what the [__] are
we going to do with that how many kids
that we're touching
like that's why i just i tell him that's
why i feel like it hasn't happened yet
because it's
that big and i think a lot of the the
stagnant part was
so i've been running this for 10 years
and the first
2010 i would say 2010 to
2014. it was like
god gave a vision you draw the vision
out but then
in doing this i was dealing with self so
in self
i was basically like dissecting me
and so i'm trying to start a program and
then
have this spiritual life and then deal
with self-control
and so i remember being at lord's gym
and it was just like i would always get
tested
playing basketball you know and i'm like
doing stuff like this lord if you don't
get him off of me
you know but it's like selfish prayer
lord if you don't get them off of me so
i can still play basketball
when i should have been like signed i'm
just going to wait
time to leave right yeah but my ego was
like
and i don't even know if you know i'm
like pride whatever at the time like no
i'm not
leaving i'm going to play basketball but
then
staying in that moment i started
changing
not more like but i'm sorry man i was
more like no you ain't gonna do nothing
no you ain't gonna do that
now i'm in his world and his level and i
remember
uh turning my back and as i turn my back
somebody's on my back choking me and i'm
all like
this could not be because you know you
mean an environment and like dude
remember that laura's jail you know i do
matt young
shoot do all this yeah i remember him
but do you remember when he choked you
out
like when he got choked out at lauren's
gym you don't want that ability right
so i got off i got out and i'm like nah
he got me where i
wanted to be now i'm about to i'm about
to fight him now
so i beat the brakes off of him but in
that
it was like i wasn't thinking about the
transformation that was happening over
my life
and just walk away so when i was going
on
you know the the the vision is already
happening
i'm working in it i'm being a leader
don't even know it can't see none of
this stuff
this moment happens after i fight this
dude and beat him up
this young kid walks up to me bawling
his eyes out
and he goes you scared me you scared me
bro i didn't feel none of those punches
or chokes but i felt that
dude i bet you did and i cried and i
never fought that day
and then after that moment happened it
was like
reconciliation started happening and i
felt like he's just a god of
reconciliation
and then that just in there i'm getting
threats by this dude the dude was a gang
member that i find i'm gonna shoot you
all this stuff that'll make you feel
scary right even though it didn't happen
he's that can put fear in your head yeah
dude two years later
i see him at daddy d's i know it's him
by his walk
i could have walked in because of fear i
walked to him
and i apologize to him oh damn and he
goes ma'am
we were just ignorant i said we was man
and reconciled
but he still had issues with me and
didn't know
the next time i see him a couple years
later we're in the church i'm already
there and he comes down he's like
whoa people are talking about oh my god
get me a car
you know and i'm all like that's cool
and all but what about reconciling
you know what about like stuff like that
forget the material stuff
so he walks in and i'm all like
oh this gotta be nuts he was all like i
ain't gonna lie
i was walking home i just felt like i'm
supposed to be here
and i just gave this testimony on
how we fought and how we reconciled and
then when i was telling this to the
congregation
if they felt it or not he gives a
testimony
like i wasn't i was just walking i felt
like i was led here but what's crazy is
i usually i used to actually think matt
was a wolf in sheep's clothing
and he just was just wow bow bow but it
but it it made me feel better because
in that walk of being persecuted people
are going to speak truth
and it was just a moment of speaking
truth but it wasn't a moment where i was
like yes
this is what i've been hoping for it was
more like well done my good and faithful
servant
you're doing what you're looking to do
it was a relief because you know because
you want him to give you that
gratification right those moments
i feel like those moments those moments
those moments of breakthrough
sometimes are exciting but there's a lot
of times where it's a relief i feel like
that happens more often that's right
i feel like that happens more often
don't flush
because of the sound whatever um
that's why i didn't we only flushed
number two um
that's why i feel like the
that that happens to me more often is
more like
oh god because i feel like
what's going on is that that negative
stuff sometimes it's subconscious
sometimes you don't know what's going on
so when you do figure out it's like damn
thank god
like thank god i figured that out and
that's what i think is most important
we're talking about um what can people
do
and and starting like in jump starting
that self-development journey
i personally think i believe in tearing
all the way down
to to to nothing like you
really do have to break yourself down
and you have to be honest and that's
where i feel like this grit comes from
like i have this
is it it's it's only negative if it's
per
if it's how it's spoken and how it's
perceived so
if i'm honest with myself people are
honestly gonna say you're negative like
during this time and i'm just
i have a little harder and a little
tougher way of
of thinking that's just it like when
when this quarantine first started
i was like okay the gym's closed i have
no equipment right
um i watched this uh game changers
documentary i tried to be vegan
for like three weeks right but i didn't
fully commit
and i couldn't let go of the meat so i
was i was eating all the imitation meat
and bro it was
[__] me up my stomach my skin
all this stuff right so i they say it's
food
they say it's food but it's absolutely
not so bro i started to get like kind of
soft like
and i'm not used to that you know i mean
i'm not used to being soft i'm not used
to being bigger i'm not used to feeling
slow
so i was honest with myself and a lot of
people say oh
you know you're so harsh that's so harsh
because i'm hitting something in them
that they don't like
so if i'm looking at myself i'm like yo
i'm fat like that's my standard just
because your standard is lower that
doesn't mean that it's negative just
because you think differently
to to identify your weaknesses is
important but a lot of people will
avoid their weaknesses the reason i got
a trainer
is because i know how to find them
exactly
but what i'm saying is is not a lot of
people want to do this because they
think it's negative
i identify my weaknesses and that's
where i started my self-development
was identifying my weaknesses right now
like i said
the the way that i jump and the way that
i move and the way that i run and then
whatever work out and the way that i
look
people think it's fine it's not fine
that's why i have a trainer because i
know i still have weaknesses
i'm trying to take it to the next
[__] level i i'm on this you know
you know i i love you know thinking
positive and thinking this way i got a
[__] coach because
everybody that i know has a coach eric
thomas is my
is my michael jordan he has a coach and
he's the number one motivational speaker
in the world
he has a [__] coach why do we think
that we're better than that we can't
if anything we should be and that's what
like with with matt
when he mentors kids too and they talk
about like
and matt will be like what do you think
lebron's doing i'm not lebron
if you're not lebron you should be doing
more than what lebron's doing
that's the [__] point but people miss
out on that and that's why i think that
that identifying your weakness is so
important and i'm humbled
every time i go to this trainer because
he knows my weaknesses because if i hid
them i'd be doing
myself an injustice i came here because
my ankles locked up and because both my
hips are locked up both ways
what are we doing right he had me doing
this exercise and i filmed it and i
[__] posted it he had me doing this
exercise
yeah man a 15 pound dumbbell one 15
pound dumbbell
i had to to go down and uh basically do
like a side squat
but my my outside foot was on a slider
so i had to slide my outside foot so i
would go directly down right
slide my outside foot up and lift the
weight at the same time
so i i as soon as i i start to slide my
foot i
i i collapse right that's the 15. he's
like oh yeah just try it again and try
it again i'm like all right cool
and then i go can't do it he's like
let's drop the weight let's drop the
weight i'm like all right cool
go to 10. as soon as i start to slide my
foot
once i go past a certain point i lose
all feeling on my hip and i don't come
back
up so i get to this point and i'm stuck
there i'm halfway down
he's like just stand up and i'm like bro
i can't he's like oh okay let's get a
five let's get a five you know
like all right okay cool you know
whatever and um
same thing five pound and then this is
where i think
what's what makes people [__] soft
and what makes people not able to
get on this development journey and i i
and the only reason i talk fitness so
much is because
fitness to me exercise stimulates the
mind
and it makes you it's such it's the
easiest way to set you up for success
i said i was going to do something i do
it it's an accomplishment right there
it's the easiest way people are in such
a long process
when am i going to get my first investor
right
10 years if i go out and and run i just
made myself feel good in 10 minutes
it's such an easy way to do it and then
this is where
i notice the difference starts coming is
my trainer is like oh no it's all good
bro
like you know tell people that you know
your trainer even has a hard time doing
i'm like bro i don't care what people
[__] think about me some people
right [__] it and and bro and i went
down in no way and i still couldn't do
it with no weight and he was like
you know it's all good like a lot of
people can't do this and i'm like dude
you're missing the [__] point this is
why i'm here
this is why i'm [__] here this is
what i want i want to do this exercise
every [__] time i train
we end on this exercise and that's what
i'm doing right right right like
that's the point is identify your
[__] weaknesses because what people
don't get
is that sharpening and always working
and and highlighting your strengths
doesn't make your weaknesses go away it
makes your weaknesses weaker
[Music]
but people fail to see that people fail
to see that
the more that the weakness goes
underneath the more that swept
underneath the rug
the more that you're sliding into dms
and you want to hide it the more the
porn you watch and all this kind of [__]
the more of those things just get swept
underneath the rug you know i talk
disrespectful my girl but
she won't leave me so you know we're
just going to sweep that under the rug
like
the more that [__] goes underneath the
rug and goes underneath unsaid
uncomfortable means growth that's why
when people get to the point where
they're working out and the lactic acid
starts to build up and they
that oh no it hurts it's enough it's
like bro you have at least 10 20 more
reps in you 100
your mind beats your body every [__]
time and that's what i've
it that's why i i just relate fitness so
much to self
because exactly what it is pain equals
growth
pain equals growth that's it are i think
it's important for anybody to have like
whatever your form of athleticism is
exactly like
dude that movement like movement it's
literally just movement a state change
so like if you're feeling bummed like so
what i do like
today for example i was feeling uh i
didn't feel like i was fully
like i didn't think that i could show up
and be the best podcast host that i
could be so
like two hours before you guys got here
i was like i'm gonna go on my run i'm
gonna go do it before i go to this
podcast
and so i run and i'm like okay where i'm
at today
is not a hundred percent my mental isn't
in the best place i can cry about that i
can sit at home
i can uh not do anything about it i can
maybe
you can [__] do something i know what
works because i've tested myself and
i've pushed myself so i'm going to go on
a run
i'm going to put on the art of war i
listened to this morning as i was
running today
um and then like by the end of my run i
feel great my body feels good and i'm
like okay cool i can do
i can do whatever i need to do it's okay
that i don't feel as good as i did on
this podcast you know
so for anybody that heard that what he
said is what i said
is a in a more articulated way and a way
for
for i personally feel like majority more
people understand
what you said was i can feel like it's
not okay and i can feel this way and i
can feel that way
but what i said is exactly what you said
earlier i said i can either be [__]
soft and i can be whatever or i know
what works and i can go do it
accept that people know except that i'm
soft you don't want to do that people
know what works you know what works and
that's what's
and that's what you get this i don't i
don't know it's victim mentality
sometimes you truly don't know but i
just have this this weird sense of
knowing that people do know what makes
them happy they do know what makes them
feel good they do know what makes them
disappointed
if you wake up every day and you're
disappointed you need to change your
whole [__] lifestyle and that's why i
say that you have to dial
all the way down to the bone get to the
very bottom strip
everything away if you have something
pulling you get rid of it
if you have things that are that are
pulling you back get rid of them
that's everything that includes people
that includes vices that includes
materials everything get rid of [__]
i was watching the the the latest at the
second or i don't know how many times
he's been on there elon musk and um
joe rogan he's selling all his [__] yeah
i saw that too
he's selling all of his stuff the dude
that started tesla
he's getting rid of all his stuff he
said because i don't want people to
think that i'm just that
that's crazy he has like all these guys
purpose bro that's what i'm saying
exactly doing something that's bigger
than just himself and what's crazy to me
is that how many people would do that
because they're defined by
he knows he's not defined by what he has
he's defined by who he is
and nobody nobody would want to do that
and what i think is that he was just so
cool calm and collected about it
joe was like what are you gonna do
around a house he's like yeah probably i
don't know
i mean i'll probably keep a couple of my
cars because he owns the company
but yeah i'm selling all my all my stuff
all my houses i have too much stuff
and it's funny he's gonna still have
money well he's not gonna have all the
[__] that goes with it
right you know well all right well so i
want to we're getting up here in time
boys i want to uh
let's send it off with a few minutes
about fear let i think we should just
just dial in on fear i mean i think it's
something that like everybody knows that
exists everybody has it everybody
like i mean whether you're like oh it's
the amygdala
response in my brain or oh it's the
fight or flight or oh it's
you know like there's so much info about
fear
that for me man when you start to
understand it when you start to
like peel back that onion layer you're
talking about like
you start to learn about yourself
because like when you learn about your
fears you learn like okay that's why i
had that fear
now i can now i can attack it so matt
what do you got on fear
go in on that um when you're talking
about
the fear of the bugs oh
this is this is bars it's so simple but
it's bars
no it's just like so you know how it is
so we have our
girls and it's crazy because
our girls um are watching example of
somebody that's scared
of bugs and when you look at these
younger girls
they're taught how to be fearful about
yours taught
you know and i believe that fear is
taught is like what you make so if
you're taught that
and then and you see the demonstration
of that
when it's your time you react and our
little girls are like that and then
there's times where i say why are you
scared who told you
to be scared and they always say
well mommy's scared and i feel like we
give them
that validation or we give them that
okay it's not okay basically
and so yeah and that's what i think it
is but it's top behavior
just like racism is top behavior just
like the things that we're
doing is it's taught you know it
was it's kind of dude when you say it's
taught it's literally like that
someone's always watching sort of thing
like
like it's not like we're purposely
trying to teach like bugs are inherently
scary
you got to remember that remember that
don't forget that it's like like our
reactions and the things we do like
there's especially there's always a
little one looking up
you know like what like what are you
you're always teaching someone around
you at all times like right
right i feel like to me i feel like fear
comes from a lack of preparation
like so right now perfect example okay
if we feel like we're fearful because
we're going to get sick
because um our jobs aren't going to
reopen um they're gonna cut the
unemployment off
they're gonna pull the plug on uh our
our podcast or our show because we're
speaking truth they're gonna
um block us on facebook they're gonna
make us not post we're gonna they're
gonna pull our
kick us off twitter and instagram and
all
it to me it's like you can't
somebody can't take something from you
that you don't give them
like there's no way you
to me if i'm grounded in who i am what i
believe in
and then acting in what i
feel like i'm called to be you can't
take anything from me that i can't give
back
and that's why i feel like right now we
live in fear
we're not living in abundance we're
living in fear they can take this they
can take that
um i'm worried about getting sick i'm
prepared
i've prepared my mind i've prepared my
body i'm not gonna get sick
like it's crazy because i got sick more
in i think it was 2018. i got sick more
in 2018
than i did in the three years
prior that i was working two jobs and it
was crazy because i had been doing this
manifesting [__]
before i even knew what it was i would
go into nike every single day
i was i would drink that vitamin c
[__] every single day
and i would and and people would be like
why do you drink that because
i'm i'm like i don't get sick i'm a
[__] machine i don't get sick
bro i got three to four hours of sleep
seven days a week for three [__]
years
and i didn't get sick one [__] time
but the second
i was like in my head and i was feeling
down i'm not good enough i'm not doing
this i'm not doing that my stomach
starts flaring up again
i start getting sick i got i was getting
colds
like every couple weeks in 2018 i was
getting colds
because i was at my relationship i
wasn't being i was whole
i was like digging burying all this [__]
that i wasn't dealing with and i was
holding it in me and i was
acting in fear and i was acting and all
this [__] and i just
i just truly believe that when you
prepared yourself when you
when you build this character that we
are like when you build up your
character
that the man that doesn't that gets
judged when no one is around and when he
gets nothing in return
and and you can't take something from a
man like that
and people like that are [__]
dangerous
and those are the people that we have
fear and like power to me
comes from somebody that doesn't have a
fear that you can't take everything that
they have and they won't get it all back
because to me i know that what's
valuable to me
right now is my brand
and the self-development thing and my
bike that i have going on my business
i've built all that and i have all that
going for me that i know that of all
that was true for me i know exactly how
to get it back
right now if your job is taken from you
a lot of people that are doing stuff
that are being those free slaves that we
talked about they
they don't have any any ground that to
be like
well if they take that away what the
[__] am i gonna do oh my god how am i
gonna pay my rent how am i gonna pay my
bills how am i gonna pay my mortgage how
can i pay my car
i don't have any of that [__] to worry
about because i know what i value and my
value is not a car i don't have a car
payment
i don't have a high rent i don't live in
a place i can't afford i don't have a
[__] credit card payment i have zero
[__] debt
zero debt zero because i know
that i don't value that [__] so it
can't be taken from me
and if you take something from me if i
get canceled if i get shut off
if i lose my job if you cut off this if
you cut off that if you cut off my
income stream i'll get it all back
there's no fear in that for me there's
no fear of me getting sick that's why i
don't wear a mask and if anybody's
offended i'm sorry
i don't wear one because i'm not afraid
of getting sick they already told us
that they
they weren't [__] necessary and now
they are now i don't believe it now i
don't believe the whole [__] thing
well you know when you're speaking and
stuff i started thinking about
another thing how fear can creep into
your
creeping to you too as well as um when
you don't have
um identity and when you don't have
value
yeah so that's what i've that's kind of
what i mean so like uh
when you're when you're grounded and who
you are when you when you
when you have built that when the man
that gets judged when he gets nothing in
return
when he has nothing and when no one is
around that's your identity
i know who i am i know what i value i
know what i
i i can do i know what i what skills i
have
like all those things make it so
we don't operate in fear i guess the the
the craziest thing would be like
you know what if they shut the world
down what if they um
what if they start forcing these uh um
vaccinations right the people that are
scared like
i you don't see people with military
training dripping about this [__]
at all because they're like if something
happens and they're forcing [__] i know
what i'm i know what i'm supposed to do
like i'm already trained in that there
is no fear for me
these people that are scared of the
people that are afraid of things that
i personally don't think exist and then
also too
if if they do start forcing [__] you
just say oh [__]
okay i mean
that's where i feel like preparation is
what i mean is what
stops you from fear i'm not i'm not
nervous in my game because i'm prepared
right
i'm not nervous in my speech because i'm
prepared there is no fear because i've
prepared
there's no fear because i've developed
development
is to me is what stops fear like i'm not
scared to go home to my girl
because i don't go home late you know
what i mean i don't say i'm gonna be
somewhere and i'm not there
i'm not out with the [__] boys at the
bar that i i've
that's why i don't fear going home
that's what because i i
act in and i built my character and i
built my identity this is what i do this
is what i don't do this is what i
represent
this is what i that what i won't
represent this is what
i can build back even if you take it all
from me i know that the person that i am
if you know the person that you are
there's no reason to live in fear
yeah it's pretty powerful i was trying
to think of like a
like preparedness because i get what you
mean when you say prepare i don't know
how to articulate it that's
that's the only thing i mean it's kind
of like with me
planning kind of comes in like so like
if i'm about to go
dj a gig like i spent a lot of hours
before
the the weeks before the day before the
day of whatever like making sure my
playlists are ready to roll
so i could have no fear of like oh [__]
what if i don't have the right song i
know that's a simplified version of what
you're yeah yeah
i know my library and so you can take
that as your own personality like yeah
yeah once you've
seen yourself you're like i know my
inner library yeah i know the things
yeah yeah yeah my fear and i'm gonna
make sure that i don't have those things
yeah so i guess
i i i don't know yeah so i guess
preparation would be the only word that
i feel like i can think of but
i mean so when this like pandemic hit i
was managing a restaurant
and all my employees that i was managing
were all laid off
everyone was freaking the [__] out
freaking out what are we gonna do
because
they're are we getting unemployment
we're getting that so we're getting that
i had money i was literally not tripping
at all
i was like bro we got to get a vacation
this is dope
i was prepared i feel like
there's just like i just feel like
there's certain things that just have to
i don't know i'm on this path or i just
want to i don't know if it's because i
have a child in the way i don't know
what it is
i just want to do i
feel like i want to dial all the way
back to like
caveman style [__] and and and get
prepared in that
like i'm gonna i'm i've never owned a
gun i've never shot a gun i've never i
just picked up a gun this year
i bought a gun i got all my i got all my
[__] i'm prepared right
i want to um i want to do some sort of
um mma i'm probably going to do jiu
jitsu and i'm going to take
a military tactical training class like
i'm prepared i don't
i'm not afraid of whatever's coming if
i'm prepared so you're not just sitting
in that fear you're like okay these
things are gonna come up i might be
actually afraid for like my
my family's life so what i'm gonna do to
be prepared is i'm gonna learn about
guns
right and and but but that takes
humility right
so i actually had a conversation with my
girl the other day which was very very
humbling for me because i finally was
like i have to have this conversation
i've been stopping it
fight or flight okay my girl is fight
i'm flight
do you know how hard it is for a male to
talk about that i turned on the music
we're driving back from the beach i
turned on music i was like babe i have
to ask you something
like this is a really hard question for
me to ask
you as your partner as the leader of
this relationship as this and as that
you know that i'm flight how do i work
on that
like because i want to be the leader i
want to be i want to be in the front
line
i'm not going to let that flight cut my
ankles exactly you know and i think what
it is
is that you she she was like you have to
disconnect emotion from the situation
because that's what happened the only
situation that we've experienced
together was when my dog was
seizing and we had a runner in the
hospital i pick her up and i'm like why
is this happening what is she doing
oh my god like what the [__] are we
gonna do she's like pick her up and put
it in the car
yeah and we'll go yeah what's next and
i'm like i'm like how do you i was like
blown away right but
having identifying your weaknesses to be
prepared
like it's hard for me at 20 years old to
walk into a gun shop and think this
dude's not going to judge me you know
what i mean
i'm like hey man i've never shot a gun
before like what would be a good you
know i mean
those kind of things like i'm going to
walk in and be like honestly i'm not the
best fighter
i'm really not that's why i don't fight
but
preparation if you think you're the best
fighter you're never even going to walk
in there though because you don't have
[__] to learn yeah
i just feel like purple yeah yeah
preparation is what preparation
wherever we can i think like to put a
pin in like everything we kind of said
you know
the preparation that we can all do as
individuals is really like all we can
actually do meaning
the like the spiritual side like the
self-worth the self-growth
i think it all ties in together yeah
dude like that's how you can prepare and
then when you're prepared you have less
fear because
they're trying to sell everybody fear
right now they're trying to like tell
you what to be mad about tell you what
to do like whatever but
when you can read the exact same
information and know like okay
maybe that's a scary thing but i'm i'm
good because i got this prepared or i'm
good because
i'm working on that i'm learning about
this sort of thing
i mean it's it's such a state of fear
right now
that's like out of our control it's like
you can't even have you can't even help
this [__] from like
so but maybe it's not out of your
control so turn off notifications how
about that take a
take a break from these social medias
like that that'll help you out with you
that's what i
that's what i feel like i feel like
common fear
would be what you were talking about
identity when i was kind of talking
about preparation i feel like this kind
of fear
to to ground and be grounded in that
to know that it's completely [__] out
of your control that's why
i'm not fearful i literally i i
i know that a lot of people say every
vote counts every voice counts i firmly
believe
that i personally the way that i believe
in it that i'm not gonna go protest and
i'm not gonna go down there
and risk my life and my freedom and all
that kind of stuff because i have
other people that i need to care about
that are close to me i think
in my actions my voice doesn't count so
i know that i know that it's out of my
hands so that's why there's no reason
for me to be scared they're gonna do
whatever they do and then we have to
react
and that's it and then you get prepared
for your reaction
so what's going to happen if this have
those conversations what's going to
happen at that
that's why i just feel like i don't know
what other way to put it other than
being prepared
and prepared and knowing that it's
completely out of your hands
it's complete all this [__] that's going
on right now protest chronovirus
they're gonna they're gonna do what they
do and we have to react and that's it
they're over the intercom telling us to
fire our lasers and our guns at each
other yeah but just
and we're putting holes in our own boat
don't put holes in your own boat look
around you
uh dude i love it listener take care of
yourself
uh let's give one more vancouver elite
outreach give me
where do i find your oh yeah so man if
you want to find me you can go to our
website it's www.vancouvereelyoutreach
at gmail oh no no no uh
dot org my badge.org so
www.vancouvereelyoutreach.org
you can find us on um youtube
ve young you can find us on instagram as
well
at vancouver elite outreach and don't be
shy right now
we're just making some moves and you may
not
can donate but maybe you want to buy
some merch or whatever man
all that stuff means the world to us
because we want to be able to be the
change that we want to see
so yeah 100 i love it dude and i checked
out your website too and i just love
like the mission statements
i watched some of the videos on there
it's like i i love what you guys
represent
i love this type and then nate i'm sure
people probably heard you on my podcast
before but go ahead and plug yourself
real quick
nicely nate jr on instagram um
i'm actually i got my own merch going on
right now
i dropped a that wasn't [__] shirt um i
got a little video coming out that kind
of tells the story behind it and i've
told it on this podcast before but it's
kind of like the
it's a millennial uh grittier version of
this too shall pass
kind of thing um i got another shirt
coming out soon so
you know hit me up on instagram i'm
doing sales off there for right now
it's been the easiest and um look out
for more stuff
cool well listener if you know anybody
in your life that could benefit from
this conversation or anything that we're
doing just plug it just take a screen
recording
do something just send it to somebody
just share it i mean we're we're
we're all three doing this kind of out
of purpose so where you know whatever
the listener can do to share and if it
spoke to you then
speak it to other people so take care of
yourselves peace out
impermanence death the end of life
do you think about this often life do
you think about the fact that life is
intertwining with death
don't you know this check out my piece
on youtube
titled jacob from the internet a thought
piece
on impermanence have a good day
you